<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hero>
    <name>Batrider</name>
    <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
    <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
    <faction>Dire</faction>
    <description>Batrider is a ranged intelligence hero who excels in lane control and harassing enemies, especially in the early phase of the game. Usually Batrider is played as a heavy support, items are not needed to utilise his abilties. Batrider is a mobile burst damage raider, capable of dealing enormous amounts of damage on stacks, at a risky close range. Before moving in for the kill, the Batrider hinders his targets with Sticky Napalm, a stacking debuff ability that slows his enemies and amplifies the damage taken from Batrider himself, be it with attacks, spells, or items. When his enemies are greatly crippled, he is ready to attack. With Flamebreak, he launches an explosive cocktail which damages and knocks back enemies in a targeted area. Then, the Batrider activates his Firefly ability, allowing the Batrider to fly high in the sky, creating a burning trail of liquid fire, scorching enemies who dare to go in his path, while giving him the ability to cross and phase through impassable grounds. With Sticky Napalm stacked, he is capable of amplifying and inflicting massive damage quickly, burning them with Flamebreak and Firefly. The Batrider then uses his ultimate, Flaming Lasso, which catches a target with a lasso, shackling and pulling them to his Firefly trail or to the clutches of his merciless allies. When these spells are used altogether, the Batrider is a dangerous enemy that enemies should be aware of, risking his own safety, but enough to cause fiery chaos and mass destruction.</description>
    <roles>
        <role>Initiator</role>
        <role>Disabler</role>
        <role>Nuker</role>
        <role>Escape</role>
    </roles>
    <attributes>
        <strengthBase>23</strengthBase>
        <strengthGain>2.4</strengthGain>
        <agilityBase>15</agilityBase>
        <agilityGain>1.5</agilityGain>
        <intelligenceBase>24</intelligenceBase>
        <intelligenceGain>2.5</intelligenceGain>
        <damageMinimum>38</damageMinimum>
        <damageMaximum>42</damageMaximum>
        <baseMoveSpeed>290</baseMoveSpeed>
        <baseArmor>2.1</baseArmor>
    </attributes>
    <ability
        name="Sticky Napalm"
        description="Drenches an area in sticky oil, amplifying damage from Batrider's attacks and abilities and slowing the movement speed and turn rate of enemies in the area. Additional casts of Sticky Napalm continue to increase damage, up to 10 stacks. The extra damage is halved against creeps."
        ability="Target Point"
        affects="Enemies"
        damage="Magical"
        blackKingBar="2"
        linkensSphere="0"
        diffusalBlade="2"
        cooldown="3"
        mana="20">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Range"
            value="700"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Radius"
            value="375"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Bonus Damage"
            value="10/15/20/25"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Duration"
            value="8"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Movement Speed Slow"
            value="3%/5%/7%/9%"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Turn Rate Slow"
            value="70%"/>
        <altDescription description="It's not uncommon to hear the Rider cackle while he increases the flammability of his opponents." />
        <notes>
            <note>All damage from Batrider's attacks, items and abilities is amplified, except for damage from Radiance, Urn of Shadows and Orb of Venom. This, too, includes buffs, such as Ancient Apparition's Chilling Touch.</note>
            <note>Bonus damage for Firefly is dealt per-second.</note>
            <note>Sticky Napalm damage is calculated as extra damage per instance, meaning that if damage is calculated per tick (0.1 seconds) it will deal extra damage per tick.</note>
            <note>Damage from Sticky Napalm is dealt as a separate instance from each instance of damage it amplifies. This makes the ability exceptionally strong at tearing apart Templar Assassin's Refraction, and makes it stack with other amplification, such as Shadow Demon's Soul Catcher especially well.</note>
            <note>Provides vision around the target point.</note>
            <note>Bonus damage is halved against non-hero units.</note>
            <note>1 stack from sticky napalm gives the full turn-rate slow.</note>
        </notes>
    </ability>
    <ability
        name="Flamebreak"
        description="Hurls a highly explosive cocktail of dangerous chemicals at the target position. Upon arriving at the location, the missile explodes, dealing damage and knocking all nearby foes away from the impact. Any unit who has been Napalmed will take additional damage from the blast."
        ability="Target Point"
        affects="Enemies"
        damage="Magical"
        blackKingBar="2"
        linkensSphere="0"
        cooldown="14"
        mana="140">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Range"
            value="1500"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Radius"
            value="375"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Damage"
            value="75/150/225/300"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Stun Duration"
            value="0.5"/>
        <altDescription description="A molotov cocktail is the weapon of choice for Batrider." />
        <notes>
            <note>The targets will be knocked back a varying distance, based on the distance to the center of the explosion (10-400 units).</note>
        </notes>
    </ability>
    <ability
        name="Firefly"
        description="Batrider takes to the skies, laying down a trail of flames from the air. The fire damages any enemies it touches, and destroys trees below Batrider. While flying, Batrider gains unobstructed movement and vision."
        ability="No Target"
        affects="Enemies"
        damage="Magical"
        blackKingBar="2"
        linkensSphere="0"
        diffusalBlade="0"
        cooldown="40"
        mana="100">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Damage Over Time"
            value="20/40/60/80"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Radius"
            value="200"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Duration"
            value="18"/>
        <altDescription description="When an enemy escapes into the Yama Raskav Jungle, most would cut through the brush to find the fugitive. Batrider just chooses to destroy the jungle along with his foes." />
        <notes>
            <note>During this Batrider can fly above units, trees and impassable terrain.</note>
            <note>If duration ends when above impassable terrain, Batrider can get stuck.</note>
            <note>The fire destroys trees when flying above them.</note>
            <note>Grants Batrider unobstructed vision, allowing him to see past trees and other obstacles.</note>
            <note>Can stack with itself.</note>
            <note>The trail persists through Batrider's death.</note>
            <note>Batrider neither triggers, nor takes damage from Land Mines during Firefly.</note>
        </notes>
    </ability>
    <ability
        name="Flaming Lasso"
        description="Lassoes an enemy and drags them in Batrider's wake. Dragged units cannot move, attack, or use abilities. Teleporting or blinking will break the lasso."
        ability="Target Unit"
        affects="Enemies"
        blackKingBar="0"
        linkensSphere="2"
        diffusalBlade="0"
        cooldown="90/75/50"
        mana="225">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Range"
            value="100"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Duration"
            value="3/3.5/4"/>
        <altDescription description="Few dare to ask to ride on the bat, as Batrider gives them free of charge." />
        <notes>
            <note>Killing Batrider or the target will break the lasso before its expiration.</note>
            <note>If Batrider moves more than 400 units in 0.05s the lasso breaks.</note>
            <note>Batrider cannot attack while using Flaming Lasso.</note>
            <note>Target can be freed with Aphotic Shield or Press The Attack.</note>
        </notes>
    </ability>
</hero>