<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<hero>
    <name>Disruptor</name>
    <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
    <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
    <faction>Radiant</faction>
    <description>Disruptor the Stormcrafter is a ranged intelligence Hero who requires good positioning to use his abilities effectively. His signature ability is Kinetic Field, a pseudo-disable that traps enemies within a small area for a long duration. Combined with his Static Storm, Disruptor can act as the initiator for a teamfight, or supplement his teammates' initiation very well. Glimpse is another powerful spell that forces enemies to watch their movements, as Disruptor can easily drag them back to a previous location to be focused down. Thunder Strike provides Disruptor with some reliable single-target damage, but more importantly grants vision on the target to prevent jukes and escapes.</description>
    <roles>
        <role>Nuker</role>
        <role>Support</role>
        <role>Initiator</role>
        <role>Disabler</role>
    </roles>
    <attributes>
        <strengthBase>19</strengthBase>
        <strengthGain>1.9</strengthGain>
        <agilityBase>15</agilityBase>
        <agilityGain>1.4</agilityGain>
        <intelligenceBase>22</intelligenceBase>
        <intelligenceGain>2.5</intelligenceGain>
        <damageMinimum>49</damageMinimum>
        <damageMaximum>53</damageMaximum>
        <baseMoveSpeed>300</baseMoveSpeed>
        <baseArmor>1.1</baseArmor>
    </attributes>
    <ability
        name="Thunder Strike"
        description="Repeatedly strikes the targeted unit with lightning. Each strike damages nearby enemy units in a small radius."
        ability="Target Unit"
        affects="Enemies"
        damage="Magical"
        blackKingBar="2"
        linkensSphere="1"
        diffusalBlade="2"
        cooldown="16"
        mana="130">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Range"
            value="800"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Radius"
            value="240"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Duration"
            value="6"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Number of Strikes"
            value="4"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Damage Per Strike"
            value="40/60/80/100"/>
        <linkensSphere description="Blocked on primary target. No interaction otherwise." />
        <altDescription description="Disruptor's charged coils occasionally overload, and a singed armor plate or tuft of fur is the enemy's result." />
        <notes>
            <note>Gives vision around the target for the duration of the spell.</note>
            <note>Deals total damage of 160/240/320/400.</note>
        </notes>
    </ability>
    <ability
        name="Glimpse"
        description="Teleports the target hero back to where it was 4 seconds ago. Instantly kills illusions."
        ability="Target Unit"
        affects="Enemy Heroes"
        blackKingBar="2"
        linkensSphere="2"
        diffusalBlade="0"
        cooldown="65/50/35/20"
        mana="160/130/100/70">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Range"
            value="600/1000/1400/1800"/>
        <altDescription description="Playing with electricity can have unexpected results." />
        <notes>
            <note>The Glimpse effect has some travel time, the target isn't instantly moved back.</note>
            <note>If the target hero dies and buys back while still being under the effect of glimpse he will be moved back.</note>
            <note>It also disrupts any command that is currently active on the player; meaning you will stand still after Glimpse.</note>
            <note>Even though BKB can block the effect, it cannot be dispelled by anything.</note>
            <note>Glimpse can be dodged by using Chaos Knights ultimate phantasm.</note>
        </notes>
    </ability>
    <ability
        name="Kinetic Field"
        description="After a short formation time, creates a circular barrier of kinetic energy that enemies can't pass."
        ability="Target Point"
        affects="Enemies"
        blackKingBar="2"
        linkensSphere="0"
        cooldown="14/13/12/11"
        mana="70">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Range"
            value="900"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Radius"
            value="325"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Formation Time"
            value="1.2"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Duration"
            value="2.5/3/3.5/4"/>
        <altDescription description="The stryder is immune to the gale-force winds that will consume its adversaries." />
        <notes>
            <note>Magic immune units can travel through the field.</note>
            <note>Only stops enemies from walking through the barrier, other sorts of movement will not be stopped.</note>
            <note>Force Staff will push units into Kinetic Field, but will not normally push units out. If a magic immune hero uses Force Staff on itself it will be pushed through the field.</note>
            <note>Gives ground vision within the field.</note>
        </notes>
    </ability>
    <ability
        name="Static Storm"
        description="Creates a damaging static storm that also silences all enemy units in the area for the duration. The damage starts off weak, but increases in power over the duration."
        ability="Target Point"
        affects="Enemies"
        damage="Magical"
        blackKingBar="2"
        linkensSphere="0"
        diffusalBlade="0"
        cooldown="85"
        mana="125/175/225">
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Range"
            value="800"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Radius"
            value="450"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Duration"
            value="5 (7*)"/>
        <abilityAttributes
            name="Maximum Damage Per Second"
            value="200/250/300"/>
        <aghanims description="Static Storm silences items, and lasts an extra 2 seconds." />
        <altDescription description="A summer squall in Druud is a hardship that only an Oglodi can survive." />
        <note>Deals total damage of 525/656.25/787.75 (1016/1263/1515*).</note>
    </ability>
    <tips>
        <tip>The vision granted on Thunder Strike's target is great for negating jukes, and at later levels Glimpse can ensure an enemy cannot escape.</tip>
        <tip>If you see an enemy teleporting to a tower, Glimpse can send them right back where they started. This can be crucial to cut off reinforcements when tower-diving.</tip>
        <tip>Kinetic Field's formation time is significant, so try and combine it with allied disables to ensure capture.</tip>
        <tip>A mark will indicate where a Glimpsed target will return, so you can cast Kinetic Field around the mark to ensure capture.</tip>
        <tip>If you can trap 3 or more enemies inside a Kinetic Field/Static Storm combo you will shift the tide of battle greatly in your team's favor as the enemies will be left without their arsenal of spells and will take significant damage over time. This is usually better achieved as a follow up to another initiation such as Magnus's Reverse Polarity.</tip>
        <tip>Due to its low starting damage, Static Storm will also benefit from an allied initiation before placement.</tip>
        <tip>Static Storm can act as an instant silence thanks to Disruptor's miniscule castpoint. Use it to interrupt channeling abilities.</tip>
        <tip>It is better to cast Static Storm first before Kinetic Field or at the same time to ensure that enemy heroes will stay in the Storm the longest amount of duration possible. By casting Kinetic Field just before enemy heroes are about to try and leave the AOE, the duration of Static Storm is maximized.</tip>
    </tips>
</hero>