<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<heroes>
    <hero>
        <name>Abaddon</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Abaddon the Lord of Avernus is a melee strength Hero known as one of the most versatile characters in Dota due to his rather low mana dependence, short spell cooldowns and a large number of viable item choices. His ability to help sustain his allies and himself plus his strong tower diving capacity give him solid lane presence. Many of his abilities offer a large sum of utility, which makes him a strong support Hero. Mist Coil serves as both a single target nuke and heal that helps shift the sustainability of both allied and enemy heroes in a lane at his will, though sacrificing a portion of his own health. Aphotic Shield holds as one of the most useful abilities in the game, able to shield a target from some damage while also able to reflect said damage to a huge area. The most important aspect is how it is able to dispel many status effects such as slows and stuns. His other abilities allow him to become a mix between a semi-carry and tank. Abaddon's passive, Curse of Avernus, allows his attacks to not only slow down his enemy, but also increase the attack and movement speed of any ally attacking the same target. With his ultimate, Borrowed Time, Abaddon is able to shift all non-HP removal damage he receives into health. When not on cooldown, Borrowed Time may activate passively when his health falls under a certain threshold, even under the most dire situations. Due to his powerful spells and versatility, Abaddon is an excellent addition to any team.</description>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.7"
            agilityBase="17"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="21"
            intelligenceGain="2.0"
            damageMinimum="55"
            damageMaximum="65"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="1.43" />
        <ability
            name="Mist Coil"
            description="Abaddon releases a coil of death that can damage an enemy unit or heal a friendly unit at the cost of some of Abaddon's health."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Units"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="5"
            mana="75">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="800"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Heal/Damage to Target"
                value="100/150/200/250"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage to Abaddon"
                value="75/100/125/150"/>
            <note>The damage to Abaddon is pure damage.</note>
            <note>Self-damage from Mist Coil can burst Aphotic Shield.</note>
            <note>Abaddon can deny himself with this ability.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Aphotic Shield"
            description="Summons dark energies around an ally unit, creating a shield that absorbs a set amount of damage before expiring. When the shield is destroyed it will burst and deal damage equal to the amount it could absorb to an area around it. Removes certain types of negative buffs and stuns on cast."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Allied Units"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="12/10/8/6"
            mana="100/105/110/115">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="675"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="15"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Absorbed Damage"
                value="110/140/170/200"/>
            <blackKingBar description="Blocked by magic immunity, but not removed by becoming magic immune." />
            <diffusalBlade description="If purged, it will explode and deal damage in its radius." />
            <note>If under the effects of Borrowed Time, Abaddon's own Aphotic Shield will not burst.</note>
            <note>Will automatically detonate and replace any existing Aphotic Shield already surrounding a target.</note>
            <note>Aphotic Shield will burst at the end of its duration if it has not absorbed sufficient damage.</note>
            <note>It will always burst for the maximum damage, regardless of how much was absorbed.</note>
            <note>Damage is calculated after all reductions.</note>
            <note>Can be used on siege creeps.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Curse of Avernus"
            description="Abaddon strikes an enemy with chilling power on each attack, causing all units who attack the slowed enemy to gain increased movement speed, along with faster attack speed, for a limited time."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Units"
            blackKingBar="0"
            diffusalBlade="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration of Slow"
                value="2.5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Slow"
                value="5/10/15/20"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration of Bonuses"
                value="4.5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Attack Speed"
                value="10/20/30/40"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="15%"/>
            <note>The Curse of Avernus buff is placed on Abaddon at the start of his attack, so he gets the bonus on his first hit. The debuff is only applied on hit.</note>
            <note>Works partially on towers. Abaddon will receive the buff from attacking a tower, however no debuff is applied to the tower so no other targets may benefit from it.</note>
            <note>Can affect allies, including creeps being denied. Enemies attacking an ally target affected by the debuff benefit from the Curse of Avernus buff.</note>
            <note>Affects magic immune targets.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Borrowed Time"
            description="When activated, most negative buffs will be removed and any damage you take will heal instead of damaging you. If the ability is not on cooldown, it will passively activate when your hitpoints drop below a certain threshold."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="60/50/40">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="3/4/5 (5/6/7*)"/>
            <aghanims description="Increases duration."/>
            <note>Borrowed Time will activate itself if you suffer damage while you have less than 400 HP.</note>
            <note>Upon casting Borrowed Time, Abaddon will effectively dodge any projectiles currently flying at him.</note>
            <note>When activated it removes most negative buffs from Abaddon, including Stuns.</note>
            <note>Borrowed Time can be manually activated.</note>
            <note>Borrowed Time is auto activated during Duel.</note>
            <note>It is possible to kill Abaddon without triggering Borrowed Time's auto-activation if he were to take damage higher than his remaining health, due to the fact that on activation of Borrowed Time, Abaddon takes the damage that activated it and then heals double the amount. Any other damage taken during the duration of Borrowed Time will deal 0 damage and heal instead.</note>
            <note>Culling Blade and Ice Blast will kill Abaddon if he fits the health threshold, even with Borrowed Time active. Ice Blast also prevents you from being healed by attacks, but you will not take any damage either for Borrowed Time's duration.</note>
            <note>If Abaddon is doomed before he hits the HP threshold, Borrowed Time will not activate.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>If you are playing the team's support hero it is usually wise to max Mist Coil and Aphotic Shield first before getting any points in Curse of Avernus as your first two skills provide a lot of utility early game ranging from healing, to debuff removal, protection and even denying yourself if needed.</tips>
        <tips>Remember that Aphotic Shield can remove stuns and slows from its target, you can use this to save your allies from many certain death situations.</tips>
        <tips>Abaddon is a very durable hero due to his unique ultimate, Borrowed Time, however do not let this fool you into diving enemies where retreating is the better option.</tips>
        <tips>Casting Aphotic Shield upon the same target before its duration has ended will automatically detonate the shield before reapplying another. Combining this tactic with its massive radius can help to increase your DPS in a teamfight or finish off enemies during a chase.</tips>
        <tips>During the early game you can use Aphotic Shield on creeps that are soon to die causing any heroes who move in for the last hit to take damage. With itemization geared toward mana regeneration this can be maintained as harassment in an Abaddon's lane support tactic. Even if the target hero realizes your tactic you can still burst your Shield by attacking the creep yourself.</tips>
        <tips>Due to his ultimate Abaddon is one of the few heroes that can dive towers even in early stages of the game, to add with his ability to chase down heroes you may also want to purchase a Mask of Madness as the extra damage Abaddon takes from activating it will not matter because of Borrowed Time.</tips>
        <tips>Most veteran players will pay attention to when Abaddon's ultimate activates and will not attack until its duration has expired, you can however heal yourself using Mist Coil during this time, or by putting yourself among enemy creeps or damage-over-time skills that have already been cast such as Jakiro's Macropyre. Pay attention however that your ultimate has a relatively short duration.</tips>
        <tips>Sometimes the best way to deal with Rupture is simply to run. Though Rupture will always outlast a manually triggered Borrowed Time, you still have total control of how much distance you can cover, as well as how much health you stand to lose or gain during Bloodseeker's ultimate.</tips>
        <tips>Since Culling Blade can kill Abaddon even through Borrowed Time you might be able to bait out the skill from an enemy Axe by manually activating your ultimate just before you hit the threshold.</tips>
        <tips>If you are planning on playing the team carry early points in Curse of Avernus will give you much needed chasing power and increased damage output and will also apply the same to your allies. In this case it might be a good choice to max Aphotic Shield before Mist Coil because you are likely to be diving the enemy a lot which will assure that your shield will burst quickly, allowing you to repeatedly cast it on yourself. Though trying to be the carry for the team is not recommended as Abaddon has much more utility as one of the most durable support heroes in the game.</tips>
        <tips>Curse of Avernus can have defensive uses as well, such as hitting an enemy that is chasing your ally to slow them down. You can also use this to save yourself as well under certain circumstances as hitting your target will reduce their movement speed by 20% while give you a 15% movement speed buff. That short boost of movement speed can sometimes save you or your allies.</tips>
        <tips>The on-hit buff and debuff of Curse of Avernus applies to any target that Abaddon may hit, including your own creeps. This means that enemy creeps will gain a speed boost after attacking one of your creeps with you. If you took an early point in Curse, use this to tinker with lane equilibrium during the laning phase.</tips>
        <tips>Note that Curse of Avernus's debuff fully stacks with unique attack modifiers. Considering this you may sometimes want to buy an Orb of Venom or Eye of Skadi which allows you to slow down a hero up to 32% or 45% respectively when used in conjunction with your passive. When playing a carry Abaddon this aids you greatly with chasing down heroes. The same can be said with a Sange and a completed Sange and Yasha that gives you both a movement speed boost and an additional slow.</tips>
        <tips>Against less experienced players it may be possible to initiate a team fight with Abaddon by diving into the enemy and absorbing most of their skills and disables since in most cases Abaddon cannot be focused down before his ultimate. This will allow your teammates to enter the fray without the fear of being disabled themselves. This strategy is very unlikely to fool more veteran players.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Alchemist</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Razzil Darkbrew the Alchemist is a melee strength hero who utilises his alchemical prowess as a strange but versatile fighter. He is an unusual carry based upon transmuting fallen enemies into large amounts of bonus gold, with both an early game and late game presence due to his large health pool and the first strike nature of his spells. His balanced statistics and the sure promise of gold for items means he can be one of the most disparately built heroes in the game. Unstable Concoction is his main contribution early on, dealing good damage and a lengthy stun. Acid Spray allows him to rapidly clear waves of creeps for his Greevil's Greed to contribute massive amounts of extra income. A well-equipped Alchemist can then use Chemical Rage to its fullest effect, as the incredible regeneration and base attack time reduction make it one of the best steroid abilities in the game.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="25"
            strengthGain="1.8"
            agilityBase="11"
            agilityGain="1.2"
            intelligenceBase="25"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="58"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="1.57" />
        <ability
            name="Acid Spray"
            description="Sprays high-pressure acid across a target area. Enemy units who step across the contaminated terrain take mixed damage per second and have their armor reduced."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Composite"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="22"
            mana="130/140/150/160">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="625"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="16"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Per Second"
                value="14/20/26/32"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Armor Reduction"
                value="3/4/5/6"/>
            <altDescription description="Using traditional Alchemy from the Darkbrew family, Razzil concocts an acid that dissolves even the toughest metals." />
            <note>Mechanical units suffer the armor reduction but do not take the composite damage.</note>
            <note>Can deal up to 224/320/416/512 damage before reductions/amplifications.</note>
            <note>As it deals composite damage, damage is reduced by magic resistance (usually 25% for heroes).</note>
            <note>Damage can be further reduced by +armor, or further amplified by -armor.</note>
            <note>Will deal significantly more damage to creeps than heroes, as creeps have no magic resistance, and tend to have lower armor.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Unstable Concoction"
            description="Alchemist brews up an unstable concoction that he can throw at an enemy hero, to stun and deal damage in an area around the explosion. The longer the concoction brews, the more damage it deals and the longer the stun. After 5 seconds, the brew reaches its maximum damage and stun time. However, after 5.5 seconds, the concoction will explode on Alchemist himself if not thrown."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemy Heroes"
            damage="Physical"
            cooldown="16"
            mana="120">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="775"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Maximum Stun Duration"
                value="1.75/2.5/3.25/4"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Maximum Damage"
                value="150/220/290/360"/>
            <altDescription description="A silver lining to the failure of turning a mountain into gold, this volatile solution has destructive potential." />
            <note>Unstable Concoction always affects a 175 area around where it explodes, including when it explodes on Alchemist.</note>
            <note>While brewing the concoction, Alchemist can still move around and take action.</note>
            <note>It will blow up on Alchemist if built up for more than 5.5 seconds without throwing, checking at 0.5 second intervals.</note>
            <note>As soon as it is thrown, the counter freezes. The concoction will not get stronger while flying or blow up mid-air.</note>
            <note>Unstable Concoction cannot be disjointed.</note>
            <note>The concoction moves at 900 speed, and provides 400/400 sight range.</note>
            <note>Damages but does not stun Alchemist if he is magic immune when it explodes on him.</note>
            <note>It is possible to deny yourself with this ability.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Throw Unstable Concoction"
            description="Throw it before it blows up!"
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemy Heroes"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="2">
            <blackKingBar description="Damages but does not stun magic immune targets. Cannot target magic immunity directly. Must be thrown before immunity is activated, or thrown at someone next to them." />
            <linkensSphere description="Only if holder is target." />
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Greevil's Greed"
            description="Alchemist gets bonus gold for killing creeps; the bonus stacks if the creeps are killed within a period of time, after which the count is reset. The bonus gold is capped at 30 gold."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            diffusalBlade="0">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="25"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Gold Per Kill"
                value="1/2/3/4"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Bonus Gold"
                value="4/6/8/10"/>
            <altDescription description="While it is not a mountain, Razzil has mastered the conversion of smaller compounds to line his pockets." />
            <note>Skill description "resets after 25 seconds" can be misleading. It's really +1 to counter when you kill a unit, -1 to counter 25 seconds after the kill.</note>
            <note>Works on Hero kills, sight wards, most summons, in addition to mechanical units (such as Plague Wards, Serpent Wards, Tombstone and some others).</note>
            <note>Greed is currently bugged to not increase the counter on denies. Note that the denies themselves do not give Alch gold either way; they are just supposed to increase the counter.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Chemical Rage"
            description="Alchemist causes his Ogre to enter a chemically induced rage, reducing base attack cooldown and increasing movement speed and regeneration."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="45"
            mana="50/100/150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="25"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Attack Time"
                value="1.4/1.2/1.0"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Health Regeneration"
                value="50/75/100"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Mana Regeneration (Base Mana Regeneration)"
                value="3/7.5/12"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Move Speed"
                value="30/40/60"/>
            <altDescription description="The brew Razzil gave to the Ogre during their prison bust has become a useful potion in the midst of combat." />
            <note>Has a 0.35 second transformation time, which can be used to dodge projectiles and stuns.</note>
            <note>Regenerates a total of 1250/1875/2500 health and 75/187.5/300 mana (less when taking the mp cost of the ability itself into account).</note>
            <note>Bonus mana regeneration is affected by mana regeneration multipliers such as Sage's Mask.</note>
            <note>Net MP Gain (norm)( +0%) : 25 / 87.5 / 150</note>
            <note>Net MP Gain (sage)(+50%) : 62.5 / 181 / 300</note>
            <note>Net MP Gain (void)(+100%) : 100 / 275 / 450</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>An early point in Greevil's Greed will significantly increase Alchemist's income.</tips>
        <tips>Smart opponents will make it difficult to land Unstable Concoction by juking and avoiding your vision, causing the backfire. It may be better to use it immediately when an enemy reaches the treeline, even if you lose damage and stun duration.</tips>
        <tips>Fully brewed, Unstable Concoction is one of the most potent stuns in the game, in both damage and stun duration. While the enemy cannot see your timer, they will still be able to see the "shaking" animation (Alchemist shaking his vials). It is imperative that you either start channeling within range, or channel a few seconds of the concoction from within fog before revealing yourself. This skill is most devastating to low armor support heroes who almost take its full damage upon impact, especially if they are softened up by acid spray.</tips>
        <tips>Use Acid Spray to dissuade enemies from defending their towers, or pushing into yours.</tips>
        <tips>Feel free to use Chemical Rage for its healing effects; it will even regenerate its own mana cost over the duration, and even more if you have %mp regen from items like Sage's Mask or Perseverance.</tips>
        <tips>Avoid skirmishes if your Chemical Rage is on cooldown, especially in the early/mid-game stage when you have few items.</tips>
        <tips>If you are in a tight spot and nowhere to run with low HP especially without Town Portal Scroll or Boots of Travel, use Unstable Concoction to commit suicide if possible.</tips>
        <tips>Chemical Rage is the strongest single target DPS booster in the game (giving a 70% boost in DPS at level 3). This means that Alchemist scales very strongly with right-click items, however at the same time Alchemist does very little damage without right-click items. This means if Alchemist is going to contribute into team battles down the road, it is imperative to get yourself some right-click.</tips>
        <tips>With Acid Spray it is possible for Alchemist to farm Ancients safely early on. This, combined with Greevil's Greed can (if used efficiently) give Alchemist incredible amounts of gold over time. It is not uncommon to have Radiance or Mjollnir by 14 minutes with this strategy.</tips>
        <tips>Beware! Heroes like Lifestealer, Slardar and Dazzle can remove the little armor you have, making you even more vulnerable and easy to kill. This is especially true in the case of Lifestealer, since Feast helps him break you down.</tips>
        <tips>Though unlisted, Medallion of Courage is a very good item for Alchemist, helping add both armor and mana regen, as well as increasing damage dealt by him. Built it in place of Ring of Basilius.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Ancient Apparition</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Kaldr the Ancient Apparition is a ranged intelligence hero. This spell-caster elemental being possesses high range, great attributes and strong semi-spammable spells. He is commonly played as a ganker or support role and due to his high agility and an attack enhancing spell, he can be played as a Semi-Carry too. His ultimate is one of the most devastating spells in the game as it can hit multiple units, has global range, freezes health regeneration, and instantly kill units if low on life.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="1.4"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="2.2"
            intelligenceBase="25"
            intelligenceGain="2.6"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="1.86" />
        <ability
            name="Cold Feet"
            description="Places a frozen hex on an enemy unit that deals damage over time, but can be dispelled by moving away from the initial cast point. If the enemy unit doesn't move out of the given range, it will be stunned and frozen in place after 4 seconds."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemy Units"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="1"
            cooldown="15/13/11/9"
            mana="150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="700"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="4"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Over Time"
                value="37.5/50/62.5/75"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stun Duration"
                value="1.25/2/2.75/3.5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Break Distance"
                value="740"/>
            <diffusalBlade description="Initial debuff can be purged; the stun cannot." />
            <altDescription description="Kaldr's presence draws those around him into a frozen void, threatening to lock them in an icy prison for eternity." />
            <note>Deals 37.5/50/62.5/75 magic damage at 0.8, 1.6, 2.5, 3.4 seconds (Total Damage: 150, 200, 250, 300)</note>
            <note>Effect ends when the unit either dies, walks 740 distance from the mark or has the debuff removed.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Ice Vortex"
            description="Creates a vortex of icy energy that slows movement speed and increases magic damage done in its range. Lasts 16 seconds."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemy Units"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="4"
            mana="80/90/100/110">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="1500"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="275"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Slow"
                value="18%/22%/26%/30%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Magic Resistance Reduction"
                value="15%/20%/25%/30%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="16"/>
            <altDescription description="Frozen, caustic winds are at the whim of Kaldr, chilling the field of battle." />
            <note>New units are checked for every 0.5 seconds.</note>
            <note>Does not affect Familiar.</note>
            <note>Provides vision in the area.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Chilling Touch"
            description="A frigid gust enchants allied heroes, granting them bonus magical damage for a given number of physical attacks, while slowing their attack speed slightly. Lasts 30 seconds."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Allied Heroes"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="50/42/34/26"
            mana="110/120/130/140">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="800"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="525"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="3/4/5/6 attacks or 30 seconds"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Magical Damage"
                value="50/60/70/80"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Attack Speed Reduction"
                value="15%"/>
            <altDescription description="The Ancient Apparition's eternal knowledge brings a frigid enchantment to his allies." />
            <note>Extra damage is its own instance of damage as opposed to added to the attack.</note>
            <note>Only works against heroes and creeps.</note>
            <note>If an attack is interrupted before dealing damage the count of attacks is not lowered.</note>
            <note>Castable attack modifiers (Drow Ranger's Frost Arrows, Viper's Poison Attack,...) will not trigger the bonus damage if it is cast (point &amp; click) instead of used via auto-cast.</note>
            <note>Each ally "hit" can deal up to 150/240/350/480 damage on his own, and if all 5 allies are "hit", this can go up to 750/1200/1750/2400 damage.</note>
            <note>The buff is always applied to Ancient Apparition even if he is not within the target area.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Ice Blast"
            description="An explosive ball of icy hail that can be used to strike targets anywhere on the map. On first use, Kaldr launches a tracer towards the targeted location. The second use marks the current location of the blast, upon which the actual projectile is launched - the greater the distance, the larger the radius affected. It deals damage to enemy units and applies a frostbite curse to units in and around the area that prevents regeneration or healing. Frostbitten units will take minor damage over time; if the units drop below a certain percentage of hitpoints, they'll instantly shatter."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemy Units"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="40"
            mana="100/125/150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="Global"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="See notes"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Frostbite Duration"
                value="8/9/10 (17*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Frostbite Damage Per Second"
                value="12.5/20/32"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="HP for Kill"
                value="10%/11%/12%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="250/350/450"/>
            <blackKingBar description="Frostbite partially goes through magic immunity. Shatter can be triggered, but it will not deal damage over time."/>
            <aghanims description="Increases duration." />
            <altDescription description="Ice storms from ages past flow through Kaldr's frosty limbs, crashing into the world and turning its inhabitants into monuments to his eternal power." />
            <note>The radius for the damage is 250+50*TimeTraveled capped at 975, The radius for HP freeze is 275 along the path of the second projectile and upon the final strike area.</note>
            <note>The instant kill doesn't work on illusions or Meepo clones.</note>
            <note>First projectile has a 1500 movement speed, stops when the caster dies or casts the second part of the skill.</note>
            <note>First projectile clears fog in a 500 radius circle at its end.</note>
            <note>Kill will be granted to the source of the damage that triggers the shatter, enemies may also deny themselves via self-damage this way.</note>
            <note>Fatal damage is 100000000 physical and clears all buffs prior damaging.</note>
            <note>HP freeze prevents all kinds of healing.</note>
            <note>The shatter damage will not kill you if you are affected by Shallow Grave.</note>
            <note>Total damage : 350/530/770 (462.5/690/994*)</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Use Cold Feet to harass in the early game, but mind your mana pool.</tips>
        <tips>Eul's Scepter of Divinity in combination with Cold Feet can almost always guarantee a stun (though at the cost of Cold Feet's damage over time). It also allows you to land a short-range Ice Blast in quick succession.</tips>
        <tips>Chilling Touch can be useful to max along with Cold Feet if you are laning with another ranged hero. The harass is extremely potent and can often push your enemies out of the lane.</tips>
        <tips>Ice Vortex can be used to slow enemies when chasing or being chased, as well as reduce their resistance. It also gives vision, so it can be used to scout the Roshan pit, ancients, trees (if someone jukes into them), high ground, and so on. The cast range is very long, so all of this can be done from a safe distance. You can even scout Roshan from the Dire Secret Shop!</tips>
        <tips>Ice Blast is a multi-purpose spell that can be cast to anywhere on the map. Use it to aid your allies in ganks, initiate team battles, finish off low-HP heroes, and clear large creep waves.</tips>
        <tips>Remember that Ice Blast prevents all healing effects from regenerating HP. Landing this skill on the enemy team at the start of a team fight will prevent healers such as Dazzle, Chen and Omniknight or a mekanism carrying hero from regenerating any hp to their team. The debuff reaches its ideal effect especially if you have an Aghanim's Scepter.</tips>
        <tips>Ancient Apparition can solo mid in the early game, as he has all the necessary tools to control his lane. AA will look to start ganking as soon as possible and use the early Ice Blasts to his team's advantage.</tips>
        <tips>In spite of his ability to solo, AA is still very potent in a dual or tri lane. Cold Feet functions well as a follow-up to an ally's stun, and Chilling Touch is able to buff every one of AA's allies, effectively multiplying its effectiveness by the number of allies you have available.</tips>
        <tips>All of Ancient Apparition's spells have incredible range. Try to avoid close combat when possible.</tips>
        <tips>You don't have an escape mechanism, so having vision of your opponents is crucial for you to survive. Ask your teammates to ward or do it yourself whenever possible.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Anti-Mage</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Anti-Mage is a fast melee Agility Carry with an emphasis on disabling and killing high-mana enemies. He has notably high agility and low base attack time, giving him high damage and scaling with his basic attacks. His signature ability is Mana Break, a passive attack modifier that makes him a huge threat to mana-reliant heroes, mainly Intelligence-based casters. In addition to granting substantial bonus damage on each attacks, its mana burn sets enemies up to be devastated by his ultimate ability, Mana Void. Blink is a highly versatile ability that allows Anti-Mage to instantly teleport short distances, thereby allowing him to escape, chase, and even farm with ease. Combined with his high base movement speed, this makes Anti-Mage a highly mobile hero at all points in the game. Spell Shield greatly increases Anti-Mage's magic resistance, allowing him to sustain more damage from enemy casters. Finally, Mana Void finishes off targets after their mana has been burnt, inflicting heavy damage to both the target and enemies surrounding the target. The damage Mana Void can potentially deal scales extremely well into the late game, as enemies' mana pools only grow larger over time. His naturally fast basic attacks combined with his powerful abilities make him extremely dangerous in the late game, allowing him to devastate enemies with ease if he is allowed to farm as a hard carry.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="20"
            strengthGain="1.2"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="2.8"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="2.14" />
        <ability
            name="Mana Break"
            description="Burns an opponent's mana on each attack. Mana Break deals 60% of the mana burned as damage to the target."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Physical"
            orbOfVenom="1"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Mana per Hit"
                value="28/40/52/64"/>
            <altDescription description="A modified technique of the Turstarkuri monks' peaceful ways is to turn magical energies on their owner." />
            <note>Can deal up to 17/24/31/38 damage per hit.</note>
            <note>Mana Burn is blocked by magic immunity.</note>
            <note>You can lifeleech the damage dealt by this skill with a Lifesteal aura.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Blink"
            description="Short distance teleportation that allows Anti-Mage to move in and out of combat."
            ability="Target Point"
            cooldown="12/9/7/5"
            mana="60">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="1000/1075/1150/1150"/>
            <altDescription description="In his encounter with the Dead Gods, Anti-Mage learned the value of being elusive." />
            <note>You can use Blink to dodge incoming projectiles.</note>
            <note>Blink has a 0.4 seconds teleportation delay.</note>
            <note>The in game tooltip is in error and clicking beyond the range of the ability will still use the maximum range of the blink as of this writing.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Spell Shield"
            description="Increases Anti-Mage's resistance to magic damage."
            ability="Passive"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Resistance"
                value="26%/34%/42%/50%"/>
            <altDescription description="Years of meditation and obsession with revenge have hardened Anti-Mage's skin against mystical opponents." />
            <note>Stacks with magic resistance items.</note>
            <note>Mana Burn is blocked by magic immunity.</note>
            <note>Total hero magic resistance for Spell shield at each level is 44.5%/50.5%/56.5%/62.5%.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Mana Void"
            description="For each point of mana missing by the target unit, damage is dealt to it and surrounding enemies. The primary target is stunned for a short duration."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="0.6/0.85/1.1"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="450"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stun Duration"
                value="0.1/0.2/0.3"/>
            <blackKingBar description="The damage is blocked, the stun is not." />
            <linkensSphere description="Blocked on primary target. No interaction otherwise." />
            <altDescription description="After bringing enemies to their knees, Anti-Mage punishes them for their use of the arcane arts." />
            <note>Stun goes through magic immunity.</note>
            <note>Has a casting delay of 0.3 seconds.</note>
            <note>Damage is calculated based on the primary target's mana, but applied to all enemies within the radius.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Blink is the most common choice for your first skill point, as its immediate benefit is better than either of your passives. Put some points into Spell Shield and stats if you are facing strong opponents or go for Mana Break if you want to be aggressive.</tips>
        <tips>Blink is a very versatile and powerful escape mechanism. You can also use it to chase, maneuver, or to avoid spells during battles.</tips>
        <tips>Manta Style is a commonly built item on Anti-Mage as your illusions can also apply Mana Break, tripling the ability's effectiveness. It also provides general stats and a means to remove most disables, especially silences, that could prevent escaping via blink.</tips>
        <tips>Mana Break is most effective against heroes with low mana pools, as you can completely deplete and disable them in less time.</tips>
        <tips>Anti-Mage becomes a real threat somewhere around level 13 if he is not underfarmed and underleveled too much. Keep farming, ignore distractions, don't hesitate to steal kills from your allies.</tips>
        <tips>Your laning phase is an absolute nightmare. Many heroes can cripple your early game by harassing you and chasing you away. Also, if you don't utilize your laning phase the game may well end before you reach Anti-Mage's maximum potential. Ask your teammates to babysit you.</tips>
        <tips>Anti-Mage has relatively low base health. If you can't kill an enemy quickly, it may be best to disengage, as a favorable fight can easily result in your own death.</tips>
        <tips>While Spell Shield provides substantial magic resistance, it is not a substitute for magic immunity as it does not block non-damage effects of enemy magic.</tips>
        <tips>Mana Void is very difficult to use to full effect. Constantly check enemies with large mana pools. Use it on enemy casters after they have used their skills and burnt most of their mana. It can absolutely devastate an enemy team if used properly. Note that it does have a short stun, allowing you to cancel spell casts and channels.</tips>
        <tips>You are utterly useless in team fights if you can't physically attack enemies. There are many ways to counter raw physical damage in DotA, especially if it's melee. Decent players will buy items like Scythe of Vyse, Blade Mail and Ghost Scepter to shut you down. Timing your entrance into the battle is everything for you.</tips>
        <tips>If you find yourself being killed quickly with stun locks and high physical damage, it is a good idea to pick up Vanguard for the HP boost and damage reduction. Alternatively, a Vitality Booster provides most of the benefit and can be later built into a Heart of Tarrasque.</tips>
        <tips>Tranquil Boots can be a viable alternative to Battlefury and Treads if your lane has a lot of harass. Rather than needing to go back to base or resorting to jungling, just back off the creep wave (preferably out of los of enemy heroes) and heal to full before you resume last hitting again. This also has the advantage of passively providing you 4 armor under heavy harass, almost a 30% reduction on incoming autoattacks!</tips>
        <tips>A quick Battle Fury will greatly increase your farming ability which will greatly help later in the game. If you do not need a Vanguard, Battlefury is a good alternative.</tips>
        <tips>Never use Blink to start a fight unless you know you can win it. Doing so could leave you stranded in a bad situation.</tips>
        <tips>Although Anti-Mage has the potential to be a carry with his extremely low BAT (Base Attack Time), with his extreme mobility and manaburn in the middle game he can be played as a ganker and semi-carry (mana burn is more effective early as armor and mana pools are lower).</tips>
        <tips>Don't just simply be farming. If the enemy is pushing Anti-Mage can push a different lane solo with a reliable escape mechanism with Blink and TP scroll and can indirectly defend by forcing the enemy to defend.</tips>
        <tips>Be very wary of heroes like Shadow Demon and Dark Seer, as illusions created from you carry the Mana Break spell as well, and combined with Anti-Mage's high Agility, could easily turn the tides of a teamfight.</tips>
        <tips>Once you get full slotted you could opt to sell your Battle Fury for a different item, but its creep clearing abilities are still very useful and sometimes critical. You should sell it if you absolutely need another item that can turn the tides, such as a Monkey King Bar.</tips>
        <tips>Many players are tempted to switch Power Treads to agility, but given your low strength gain (1.2), it may be better to keep them on strength. This is especially true early game, or if you opt for a Battle Fury instead of a Vanguard.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Axe</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Mogul Khan the Axe is a savage melee strength hero, infamous for creating chaos in battle and thriving off of it. He is commonly played as an initiator with a large semi-carry presence that quickly transitions into a support role later in the game. His fighting style demands that he gets up close and very personal. He can taunt enemies into targeting him and counters those who try to strike him with a sweeping Counter Helix that slashes all enemies at melee range. Axe has a tendency to draw opponents so deep in the fight that they do not have a chance to escape, each soul he draws infusing his own love of war; his ultimate, Culling Blade bolsters that talent with an attack that unconditionally kills a unit with low health.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="25"
            strengthGain="2.5"
            agilityBase="20"
            agilityGain="2.2"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.6"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="1.86" />
        <ability
            name="Berserker's Call"
            description="Mogul Khan the Axe is a savage melee strength hero, infamous for creating chaos in battle and thriving off of it. He is commonly played as an initiator with a large semi-carry presence that quickly transitions into a support role later in the game. His fighting style demands that he gets up close and very personal. He can taunt enemies into targeting him and counters those who try to strike him with a sweeping Counter Helix that slashes all enemies at melee range. Axe has a tendency to draw opponents so deep in the fight that they do not have a chance to escape, each soul he draws infusing his own love of war; his ultimate, Culling Blade bolsters that talent with an attack that unconditionally kills a unit with low health."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="16/14/12/10"
            mana="80/90/100/110">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Armor"
                value="40"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="2/2.4/2.8/3.2"/>
            <altDescription description="Mogul Khan's warcry taunts opponents into engaging in an unconquerable battle with the Axe." />
            <note>Berserker's Call affects invisible units, as well as units with magic immunity.</note>
            <note>Enemies who are taunted by Berserker's Call will be frozen for the duration if Axe dies or couldn't be attacked.</note>
            <note>Does not affect towers.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Battle Hunger"
            description="Enrages an enemy unit, causing it to be slowed and take damage over time until it kills another unit or the duration ends. Axe gains movement speed for each unit affected with Battle Hunger."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="20/15/10/5"
            mana="75/85/95/105">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="10/12/14/16"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Slow"
                value="10%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="10%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Per Second"
                value="15/20/25/30"/>
            <altDescription description="Ordinary heroes cannot withstand Mogul Khan's rage for battle, such that it injures them until it is satisfied." />
            <note>Killing illusions, denying a friendly creep or destroying buildings will also remove the debuff.</note>
            <note>Units affected by Battle Hunger cannot be denied.</note>
            <note>Killing using summons does not remove debuff.</note>
            <note>Has a maximum range of 900.</note>
            <note>Total Damage: 150/240/350/480.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Counter Helix"
            description="When attacked, Axe performs a helix counter attack, dealing damage to all nearby enemies."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            mantaStyle="2"
            cooldown="0.45/0.4/0.35/0.3">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="275"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Chance to Helix"
                value="17%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100/135/170/205"/>
            <altDescription description="Axe is the only reinforcements this army needs." />
            <note>Counter Helix checks for triggering whenever an attack against Axe begins, not when Axe is actually damaged by said attack.</note>
            <note>Attacks from mechanical units cannot trigger Counter Helix. This includes Towers, Siege Creeps, Plague Wards, Serpent Wards, the Death Ward, and some others.</note>
            <note>Does damage mechanical units like Siege units.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Culling Blade"
            description="Axe spots weakness and strikes, dealing moderate damage but instantly killing an enemy unit with low health. When an enemy unit is killed in this way, Axe and nearby allied units gain bonus movement speed."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="75/65/55 (6*) (0**)"
            mana="60/120/180">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Kill Threshold"
                value="250/350/450 (300/450/625*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="150/250/300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="150"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="40%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Attack Speed"
                value="40%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Radius"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Duration"
                value="6 (10*)"/>
            <blackKingBar description="Instant kill can't be blocked, normal hit can." />
            <diffusalBlade description="Buff after cull can be purged." />
            <aghanims description="Decreases cooldown and increases damage." />
            <altDescription description="Mogul Khan is the embodiment of battle and fury, launching into a gruesome fatality against those who dare engage the Axe in combat." />
            <note>Does not go on cooldown if it successfully kills a hero.</note>
            <note>If the target is under the HP threshold, Culling Blade does exactly the target's remaining health in unmitigable damage.</note>
            <note>The killing blow goes through magic immunity.</note>
            <note>The killing blow removes all buffs from the target unit before killing it.</note>
            <note>This includes any hero that is under the effects of Dazzle's Shallow Grave as well.</note>
            <note>Roshan can be killed by Culling Blade.</note>
            <note>You can steal last hits from Necrophos's Reaper's Scythe by using this ability.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Axe is especially dangerous early game with high starting statistics and the speed from Battle Hunger contributing to his ability to push up to the enemy tower relatively safely, even for a semi-carry.</tips>
        <tips>Berserker's Call provides the full armor bonus at level one. It is the primary factor in his ability to survive physical damage without good statistics.</tips>
        <tips>Resist using Culling Blade when not roaming. While Axe is powerful early game, he levels stat-wise fairly badly, and it is best to drop kills to a carry past the point when a team acquires their ultimate.</tips>
        <tips>Items such as the Vanguard, Hood of Defiance and the Shiva's Guard are essential as they help reduce the damage being dealt to Axe while he tanks and initiates a battle without a Blink Dagger. With a Blink Dagger, this aspect can be ignored when initiating to an extent.</tips>
        <tips>During the early phase of the game, a Stout Shield is all Axe needs to survive the lane. If possible, instead of fighting along with allied creeps, Axe can try to go and clash with the enemy creeps by himself with Counter Helix allowing him to take down unstacked creeps by himself.</tips>
        <tips>A more advanced technique used by players is to max out Battle Hunger by Level 7. This enables Axe to constantly deal damage over time (dots) in the lane, dealing crippling damage and blocking any potential to push or counterpush. This meshes well with Axe's capability to tank and keep the enemy at bay while stopping them from last hitting or denying creeps, allowing Battle Hunger deal its full damage.</tips>
        <tips>If Axe is going against two weak melee heroes in a lane without sufficient burst damage (such as Phantom Assassin or Spirit Breaker, etc.), do not hesitate to stand between them and their creeps. It allows for complete lane dominance as they cannot last hit and it denies them of experience and gold as Counter Helix hurts a lot early game.</tips>
        <tips>You can put "dota_health_per_vertical_marker 300" in the console without quotes to easily find the instakill hp thresholds for Axe's ultimate. Change the number according to Axe's ultimate. This sets each bar of health to the value you set, which means when they are under 1 bar of health, you can ultimate. This can also be applied to Dagon, but Magic Resist should be factored in.</tips>
        <tips>Axe is an excellent counter-pick to heroes with abilities that can greatly increase their attack speed (i.e. Ursa, Troll Warlord), as a combination of Berserker's Call and Blade Mail can be devastating to such heroes, especially if Counter Helix procs numerous times.</tips>
        <tips>Instead of using Berserker's Call to draw creep aggro in lane, it's usually better to right click enemy hero (which automatically pulls the creep aggro). It applies to any enemy heroes visible on map, thus you can pull aggro by standing in the middle of wave and right clicking visible enemy on the other side of the map.</tips>
        <tips>Soul Ring can provide all of the mana needed through the early and midgame. Use this in cojunction with a form of HP regeneration such as Tranquil Boots or a Vanguard.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Bane</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Atropos the Bane Elemental, also known simply as Bane, is a ranged intelligence Hero, possessing dark and nightmarish abilities that give him strong disabling, ganking, and nuking prowess. Mostly played as a support, he has some of the highest starting stats of any hero, yet is unique in the sense that all his attributes and stat growths are equivalent. In addition, he possesses four highly potent single-target spells, which if used properly can more than make up for his complete lack of area of effect presence and pushing power. Enfeeble reduces the target's attack damage by a tremendous amount, which can highly reduce an attack-reliant enemy hero's effectiveness from as early as the laning stage all the way to the endgame. Brain Sap is a nuke that deals hefty pure damage to the target, healing himself for the same amount as well. Nightmare puts a unit to sleep, completely disabling for several seconds and dealing minor damage per second. If the slept target is physically attacked, it wakes up and the spell transfers to the attacker (spells will also wake the target up, but will not transfer the effect to the caster). Finally, Bane's Fiend's Grip is a channeling spell that completely disables the target for several seconds, dealing heavy damage per second and giving Bane some mana back as well. Bane's debilitating lockdown abilities are what make him an invaluable support to allies, and a feared one for enemies.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.1"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="2.1"
            intelligenceBase="22"
            intelligenceGain="2.1"
            damageMinimum="55"
            damageMaximum="61"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="4.14" />
        <ability
            name="Enfeeble"
            description="Weakens an enemy unit, reducing its physical damage. Lasts 20 seconds."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="10"
            mana="95/105/115/125">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="1000"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="20"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Attack Damage Reduction"
                value="30/60/90/120"/>
            <blackKingBar description="Blocked by magic immunity, but can't be dispelled by it." />
            <altDescription description="Even the mightiest of warriors crumble before the terror of Atropos." />
            <note>Unable to target Ancients</note>
            <note>Even if Black King Bar can block it, this spell can't be dispelled.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Brain Sap"
            description="Feasts on the vital energies of an enemy unit, dealing damage and gaining health equal to the damage dealt."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Pure"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="14"
            mana="125/150/175/200">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Health Absorbed"
                value="90/160/230/300"/>
            <altDescription description="Atropos finds no greater pleasure than to harvest the fear he creates." />
            <note>Bane always receives the full amount of health, regardless of the amount of damage dealt.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Nightmare"
            description="Puts the target enemy or friendly Hero to sleep and deals damage per second. Sleeping units are awakened when attacked, but the Nightmare passes to the attacking unit."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Units"
            damage="HP Removal"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="15"
            mana="165">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500/550/600/650"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="4/5/6/7"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Health Drain per Second"
                value="20"/>
            <altDescription description="A stolen prowess from the goddess Nyctasha is to put his prey into forever sleep." />
            <note>The target will wake up on receiving any type of damage other than HP Removal.</note>
            <note>Nightmare deals damage to allies and himself, so it can be used to deny heroes or himself.</note>
            <note>Any source of damage except Nightmare will awaken the unit, but only physical attacks cause the Nightmare to be transferred.</note>
            <note>In the first second of Nightmare, the unit is invulnerable.</note>
            <note>Bane can wake himself up from Nightmare.</note>
            <note>Deal a total of 80/100/120/140 damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Nightmare End"
            description="Wakes Bane up from Nightmare."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self">
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Fiend's Grip"
            description="CHANNELED - Grips an enemy unit, disabling it and causing heavy damage over time, while stealing mana every second based on the unit's maximum mana."
            ability="Channeled"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="100"
            mana="200/300/400">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="625"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="5 (7*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage per Second"
                value="100/155/215 (155/215/270*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Mana Transfer per Second"
                value="5% (10%) of target's max mana"/>
            <blackKingBar description="Will do no damage." />
            <aghanims description="Increases damage per second, mana drain, and duration." />
            <altDescription description="Victims of Atropos are frequently torn apart by vivid conjurations of their own nightmares." />
            <note>Using Fiend's Grip on a magic immune unit will still disable and drain mana, but no damage will be dealt to the targeted unit.</note>
            <note>Deal a total of 500/775/1075 (1085/1505/1890*) damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Between levels 6-12 Bane is comparatively a very powerful hero, and assuming you maxed his Brain Sap (as you should under all circumstances) you will be able to solo most heroes by means of Fiend's Grip followed by Brain Sap. It is necessary to get kills during this phase of the game; as if Bane is not well-geared and leveled up later in the game, he will be relegated to a support unit.</tips>
        <tips>It is important for the player to judge when to change roles; as mentioned above, Bane should gank constantly in the middle of the game to gain a gold advantage and avoid getting shut down or subjugated to a conservative support role. A well-managed Bane can change the outcome of a team fight in the late game with effective use of items such as Necronomicon, Scythe of Vyse, and Aghanim's Scepter.</tips>
        <tips>New or unseasoned players have a tendency to attack targets under Nightmare. Before the game starts, make sure to warn them about it.</tips>
        <tips>Bane is not an initiator; despite having two disables, he is far too delicate to withstand the initial retaliation. Instead, he should hide until such time as his abilities become crucial when the team fight has ensued(preventing escapes, finishing off enemy heroes with Brain Sap, etc.).</tips>
        <tips>Avoid heroes with stuns, as they can interrupt Fiend's Grip. If you must deal with them, incapacitate them via Nightmare, a Scythe of Vyse, or Fiend's Grip itself. Picking Bane in a match against several heroes with disables is unwise. Black King Bar is typically an effective first major item to build on Bane if you need to help your team disable someone before they retaliate.</tips>
        <tips>If the enemy team lack area-of-effect stuns or interrupts, a Shadow Blade can make your ultimate harder to stop, since your opponents must first reveal you and then interrupt you. As with all similar abilities, you can activate invisibility without breaking your channel. While Shadow Blade is also effective for ganking solo heroes and escaping, you should still get Black King Bar instead if the enemy team have ranged AoE interrupts such as those possessed by Lina, Drow, Dark Seer, Death Prophet etcetera.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Batrider</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Batrider is a ranged intelligence hero who excels in lane control and harassing enemies, especially in the early phase of the game. Usually Batrider is played as a heavy support, items are not needed to utilise his abilties. Batrider is a mobile burst damage raider, capable of dealing enormous amounts of damage on stacks, at a risky close range. Before moving in for the kill, the Batrider hinders his targets with Sticky Napalm, a stacking debuff skill that slows his enemies and amplifies the damage taken from Batrider himself, be it with attacks, spells, or items. When his enemies are greatly crippled, he is ready to attack. With Flamebreak, he launches an explosive cocktail which damages and knocks back enemies in a targeted area. Then, the Batrider activates his Firefly ability, allowing the Batrider to fly high in the sky, creating a burning trail of liquid fire, scorching enemies who dare to go in his path, while giving him the ability to cross and phase through impassable grounds. With Sticky Napalm stacked, he is capable of amplifying and inflicting massive damage quickly, burning them with Flamebreak and Firefly. The Batrider then uses his ultimate, Flaming Lasso, which catches a target with a lasso, shackling and pulling them to his Firefly trail or to the clutches of his merciless allies. When these spells are used altogether, the Batrider is a dangerous enemy that enemies should be aware of, risking his own safety, but enough to cause fiery chaos and mass destruction.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.4"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="24"
            intelligenceGain="2.5"
            damageMinimum="38"
            damageMaximum="42"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="2.14" />
        <ability
            name="Sticky Napalm"
            description="Drenches an area in sticky oil, amplifying damage from Batrider's attacks and abilities and slowing the movement speed and turn rate of enemies in the area. Additional casts of Sticky Napalm continue to increase damage, up to 10 stacks."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="3"
            mana="20">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="700"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="375"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="10/15/20/25"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="8"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Slow"
                value="3%/5%/7%/9%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Turn Rate Slow"
                value="70%"/>
            <altDescription description="It's not uncommon to hear the Rider cackle while he increases the flammability of his opponents." />
            <note>All damage from Batrider's attacks, items and abilities is amplified, except for damage from Radiance, Urn of Shadows and Orb of Venom. This, too, includes buffs, such as Ancient Apparition's Chilling Touch.</note>
            <note>Bonus damage for Firefly is dealt per-second.</note>
            <note>Sticky Napalm damage is calculated as extra damage per instance, meaning that if damage is calculated per tick (0.1 seconds) it will deal extra damage per tick.</note>
            <note>Damage from Sticky Napalm is dealt as a separate instance from each instance of damage it amplifies. This makes the ability exceptionally strong at tearing apart Templar Assassin's Refraction, and makes it stack with other amplification, such as Shadow Demon's Soul Catcher especially well.</note>
            <note>Provides vision around the target point.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Flamebreak"
            description="Hurls a highly explosive cocktail of dangerous chemicals at the target position. Upon arriving at the location, the missile explodes, dealing damage and knocking all nearby foes away from the impact. Any unit who has been Napalmed will take additional damage from the blast."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="14"
            mana="140">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="1500"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="375"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="75/150/225/300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stun Duration"
                value="0.5"/>
            <altDescription description="A molotov cocktail is the weapon of choice for Batrider." />
            <note>The targets will be knocked back a varying distance, based on the distance to the center of the explosion (10-400 units).</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Firefly"
            description="Batrider takes to the skies, laying down a flaming trail from the air. While flying, the trail of fire destroys trees and damages enemies in its path, and Batrider gains the movement capabilities of a flying unit."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="40"
            mana="100">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Over Time"
                value="20/40/60/80"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="200"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="18"/>
            <altDescription description="When an enemy escapes into the Yama Raskav Jungle, most would cut through the brush to find the fugitive. Batrider just chooses to destroy the jungle along with his foes." />
            <note>During this Batrider can fly above units, trees and impassable terrain.</note>
            <note>If duration ends when above impassable terrain, Batrider can get stuck.</note>
            <note>The fire destroys trees when flying above them.</note>
            <note>Grants Batrider unobstructed vision, allowing him to see past trees and other obstacles.</note>
            <note>Can stack with itself.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Flaming Lasso"
            description="Lassoes an enemy and drags them in Batrider's wake. Dragged units cannot move, attack, or use abilities. Teleporting or blinking will break the lasso."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="90/70/50"
            mana="150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="100"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="3/3.5/4"/>
            <altDescription description="Few dare to ask to ride on the bat, as Batrider gives them free of charge." />
            <note>Killing Batrider or the target will break the lasso before its expiration.</note>
            <note>If Batrider moves more than 400 units in 0.05s the lasso breaks.</note>
            <note>Batrider cannot attack while using Flaming Lasso.</note>
        </ability>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Beastmaster</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Karroch the Beastmaster is a melee strength hero whose unique power takes the form of summons with exaggerated unit utility. His thralls provide extreme amounts of sight and have ability to reduce the attackspeed of targeted units. In addition, he has the longest lasting single reliable stun in the game. He is an effective support with good disabling ability in team fights. His strengths lie primarily in the slow debuff his Boar inflicts and ability to easily provide vision at crucial locations on the map. His ultimate, the stunning Primal Roar and Wild Axes allow him to deal massive damage at a distance. Though he is able to easily take down undefended targets in the early game, most of his abilities do not directly combo with each other, although the debiliating effects he brings to a fight can greatly assist allies (along with his passive attack speed boost aura).</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.2"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="1.6"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.9"
            damageMinimum="56"
            damageMaximum="60"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="4.57" />
        <ability
            name="Wild Axes"
            description="Beastmaster sends his axes flying and calls them home again, slicing through enemy units and trees along their path. Each axe can hit an enemy once."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Composite"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="13"
            mana="120">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="1300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="90/120/150/180"/>
            <altDescription description="While learning to maneuver in nature alone, the Beastmaster also mastered the use of a pair of tomahawks, adept at cutting down trees as well as adversaries." />
            <note>This ability destroys trees.</note>
            <note>The flying axes give flying vision.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Call of the Wild (Hawk)"
            description="Beastmaster calls allies in the form of a watchful Hawk. Level 1: Summons a Scout Hawk. Level 2: Summons a Scout Hawk. Level 3: Summons a Greater Hawk. Level 4: Summons a Greater Hawk."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="40"
            mana="15">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Hawk Duration"
                value="60"/>
            <altDescription description="After befriending the strange beast of his childhood, Beastmaster has learned to call to animals in times of need." />
            <note>The hawk gives 30/30/65/65 gold.</note>
            <note>Uses a 0.3 cast point instead of the normal 0.5 cast point.</note>
            <note>Will not destroy a previous summon if this ability is used again before the Hawk's duration expires.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Call of the Wild (Boar)"
            description="Beastmaster calls allies in the form of a powerful Boar. Level 1: Not Available. Level 2: Summons a Lesser Boar. Level 3: Summons a Lesser Boar. Level 4: Summons a Greater Boar."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="40"
            mana="15">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Boar Duration"
                value="60"/>
            <altDescription description="After befriending the strange beast of his childhood, Beastmaster has learned to call to animals in times of need." />
            <note>The boar gives 26-38 gold.</note>
            <note>Uses a 0.3 cast point instead of the normal 0.5 cast point.</note>
            <note>Will not destroy a previous summon if this ability is used again before the Boar's duration expires.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Inner Beast"
            description="Untaps the inner fury of allies, passively increasing their attack speed."
            ability="Aura"
            affects="Allies">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Attack Speed"
                value="15/25/35/45"/>
            <altDescription description="Beastmaster's ability to incite the innate strength of animals was seen in the mauling of the king of Slom." />
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Primal Roar"
            description="A deafening roar that deals damage and stuns the target enemy unit, while opening a path between Beastmaster and his prey. Nearby enemies also take damage and have their movement speed and attack rate reduced. Upgradable by Aghanim's Scepter."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="1"
            cooldown="80/75/70 (45*)"
            mana="150/175/200">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600 (950*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stun Duration"
                value="3/3.5/4"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="250"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Slow"
                value="50%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Attack Slow"
                value="50%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Slow Duration"
                value="2/3/4"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="200/250/300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Side Damage"
                value="100/200/300"/>
            <blackKingBar description="The damage is blocked, the stun or the push is not." />
            <linkensSphere description="Blocked if user is target." />
            <diffusalBlade description="Side target's slow can be purged, the main target's stun cannot." />
            <aghanims description="Decreases cooldown, increases cast range." />
            <altDescription description="Beastmaster's ability to incite the innate strength of animals was seen in the mauling of the king of Slom." />
            <note>The slow and stun go through magic immunity, but the damage does not.</note>
            <note>Only enemy units are shoved aside from the path of the roar.</note>
            <note>Primal Roar can be used on Couriers, but won't do any damage since couriers are magic immune.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>His Wild Axes skill is a powerful farming tool.</tips>
        <tips>Beastmaster can stack/farm ancients incredibly effectively with Wild Axes since it can affect magic immune units.</tips>
        <tips>Although his skills have a long range, Blink Dagger is still useful for lining up Primal Roar.</tips>
        <tips>Beastmaster works well alongside carries who already have attack power but lack attack speed (Like Sven and Tiny) due to his attack speed boosting aura.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Bloodseeker</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Strygwyr the Bloodseeker is a melee agility hero imbued with dreadful powers to fuel violence and rip enemies apart in the heat of close combat. He can drive targets into a maddened Bloodrage, increasing the damage of their attacks, preventing them from casting spells and bleeding their life in the frenzy. His speed is unmatched when he senses the blood of the dying, and from this perception none can escape. His own health is never a problem, as he can salve his wounds merely by bathing in the blood of the fallen. His ultimate, Rupture, sunders the skin of his victims, causing them to trail their life force behind if they dare to flee.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="24"
            agilityGain="3.0"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.7"
            damageMinimum="53"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="3.43" />
        <ability
            name="Bloodrage"
            description="Drives a unit into a bloodthirsty rage, during which it has higher attack damage, but cannot cast spells and takes damage every second. Bloodrage dispels the target before applying its buff."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Units"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="1"
            cooldown="12/10/8/6"
            mana="80">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="800"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="6/7/8/9"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Increased Damage"
                value="30%/60%/90%/120%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Per Second"
                value="20"/>
            <diffusalBlade description="Not purgeable by allies." />
            <altDescription description="Strygwyr shares his animalistic thirst for bloodshed." />
            <note>Can be used to deny self or allies.</note>
            <note>Purges the target and removes the ethereal state from enemies.</note>
            <note>Does not amplify damage directly gained from items (such as Radiance), only base damage and damage gained from the hero's primary attribute.</note>
            <note>Deals a total of 120/140/160/180 damage to the target unit.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Blood Bath"
            description="Bloodseeker revels in combat, gaining health with every unit he kills or an enemy hero dies within a 325 radius of Bloodseeker. The health gained is a percentage of the killed unit's maximum HP."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Regeneration from Hero's maximum HP"
                value="10%/20%/30%/40%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Regeneration from Creep's maximum HP"
                value="10%/15%/20%/25%"/>
            <altDescription description="Flayed ones bathing in the blood of the recently fallen is a terrifying sight on the field of battle." />
            <note>Denied creeps and heroes will trigger Bloodbath, but illusions will not.</note>
            <note>Bloodseeker will regenerate hp regardless of how he killed the unit, be it with spells, items or attacks.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Thirst"
            description="Enables Bloodseeker to sense enemy Heroes with health below a certain percentage, giving him vision of that unit, increased movement speed and increased damage. Bonuses stack per Hero. Bloodseeker gains True Sight of enemy heroes below half their visiblity threshold."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            mantaStyle="0">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="Global"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="Until no nearby valid target exists"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="5%/15%/25%/35%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus damage"
                value="5/15/25/35"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Thirst HP percentage detection"
                value="50% of target HP (True sight is 25%)"/>
            <altDescription description="Strygwyr becomes frenzied when blood is spilled." />
            <note>Thirst is not triggered by Illusions.</note>
            <note>When active, movement speed cap is removed on your hero.</note>
            <note>Bonus stacks for each unit within HP threshold.</note>
            <note>Does not grant full vision on detected enemy heroes, it only shows their model.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Rupture"
            description="Causes an enemy unit's skin to rupture, dealing massive damage. If the unit moves while under the effect of Rupture, it takes a percentage of the distance traveled as damage."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="HP Removal"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="70/60/50"
            mana="150/200/250">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="1000"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="7/8/9"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Initial Damage"
                value="150/250/350"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Distance Moved Damage"
                value="20%/40%/60%"/>
            <altDescription description="When the Bloodseeker hunts you, injuries become fatalities." />
            <note>If the affected unit moves more than 1300 distance in 0.25 seconds, it will not receive any damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Bloodseeker, whilst being an efficient jungler and dual laner, is also a prime choice for solo mid, as it gives him easy access to the side lanes for ganking.</tips>
        <tips>Reaching level six as quickly as possible should be a priority of the player; ganks should not usually be attempted before he has his ultimate.</tips>
        <tips>Blood Bath gives Bloodseeker significant staying power in lane, healing him whenever he last hits or denies a creep.</tips>
        <tips>An early Quelling Blade will help you get the most benefit out of Blood Bath.</tips>
        <tips>Thirst is especially useful for allowing for clear targets on a team with no map vision or communication. Otherwise, its best for greatly increasing the risk under which weakened enemies move out or providing conditional speed.</tips>
        <tips>Leveling Bloodrage causes it to turn into a steroid with a more powerful attack damage buff on every level, but it also serves as a powerful early game nuke and disable. The steroid effect on a fully-leveled Bloodrage is very powerful, often on par with the full arsenal of buffs carried by a given team.</tips>
        <tips>Bloodrage should be cast on enemies beginning an engagement to prevent nukes. If Bloodseeker is laning against supports it is an extremely useful spell. Late game, it becomes a dedicated steroid for Bloodseeker or other carries or to twitch disable big caster threats such as Enigma or Earthshaker.</tips>
        <tips>At level 3 it can be used almost continuously, since it has a short casting animation.</tips>
        <tips>Rupture is one of the best skills to intercept an enemy hero that is chasing you or your allies, especially since it goes through magic immunity and does full damage regardless of armor and magic resistance. Heroes with high mobility like Anti-Mage, Lycan, Luna, Queen of Pain or Night Stalker suffer devastating damage when Ruptured as they are chasing or running away.</tips>
        <tips>When ganking it is sometimes best to save your Rupture for when your target begins running away rather than right at the beginning of the gank. You may want to follow up on an allied disable using Bloodrage to silence the target and saving Rupture should the target not die during the initial damage done.</tips>
        <tips>Bloodseeker is the fastest hero in the game when Thirst is level 4 with 5 heroes below 50% of their max hp.</tips>
        <tips>Each individual Meepo will add to the Thirst bonus stack.</tips>
        <tips>Maximum speed with Thirst is 1852. To reach it, you need Eul's Scepter of Divinity, Sange and Yasha, Boots of Travel, Phase Boots, Mask of Madness, Shadow Blade (on Bloodseeker, activate items in order MoM-Shadow Blade-Phase Boots), Kobold Foreman's Speed Aura, Spirit Breaker's Empowering Haste Aura, Io's Tether, Sven's Warcry, Ogre Magi's Bloodlust, Necronomicon Archer's Attack Speed and Movement Aura and activated Drum of Endurance.</tips>
        <tips>Due to the passive Blood Bath being able to heal you upon killing any enemy unit. It is advisable not to spend gold on Morbid Mask, skipping therefore on Lifesteal items. Moreover, Bloodseeker should have a high damage output in order for faster killing, which subsequently gives faster healing.</tips>
        <tips>Skull Basher or Abyssal Blade can opt to be taken if your team lacks disables and your enemies are using Teleportation spells like Town Portal Scrolls to escape your onslaught.</tips>
        <tips>Force Staff, in conjunction with Rupture can cause significant burst damage (120/240/360) to enemy heroes by forcing them to move. It also serves as a quick escape tool, something that Bloodseeker does not naturally possess. However, it should be noted that the burst damage is relatively little to the level of your enemies and the level of your ultimate, and may just potentially push your target to safety.</tips>
        <tips>Helm of the Dominator can introduce interesting new utility if Bloodrage is used as a steroid.</tips>
        <tips>Armlet of Mordiggian can be picked up if you are confident in your killing power. It synergizes well with Blood Bath and Bloodrage's damage increase, but can also make you easier to kill, especially when focused.</tips>
        <tips>Rod of Atos can give Bloodseeker even better chasing ability and can be bought if you don't want to rely on Sange's random Maim chance. However, the 25 bonus Intelligence is wasted on Bloodseeker.</tips>
        <tips>Shadow Blade can be used to surprise your enemies, especially when they are alone. Backstab damage, movement speed and attack speed boosts your hunting ability along with your Thirst.</tips>
        <tips>Bloodseeker is really good counter for Slark due to Thirst. You will make him unable to regen from Shadow Dance everywhere on map when his hp is below 50%.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Bounty Hunter</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="1.8"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="3.0"
            intelligenceBase="19"
            intelligenceGain="1.4"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="6.0" />
        <ability
            name="Shuriken Toss"
            description="Hurls a deadly shuriken at an enemy unit, dealing damage and ministunning the target."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="10"
            mana="90/115/135/155">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="650"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100/200/250/325"/>
            <altDescription description="While the shuriken may be small, Gondar's precise aim can cause critical damage." />
            <note>Mini-stuns the target on impact.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Jinada"
            description="Bounty Hunter plans his next hit, passively adding a critical strike and maim to his next attack."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="12/10/8/6">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="3"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Slow"
                value="25%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Attack Speed Slow"
                value="25"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Critical Damage"
                value="150%/175%/200%/250%"/>
            <altDescription description="Whispering an enchantment he learned from Soruq to his faithful blades, Gondar targets vital tendons and joints to disable his opponents." />
            <note>Jinada does not amplify the damage of your Shadow Walk ability.</note>
            <note>Though it stacks with Shadow Walk damage. Shadow Walk and Jinada total damage is: (Autoattack * Jinada crit multiplier) + (Shadow Walk bonus damage).</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Shadow Walk"
            description="Bounty Hunter becomes invisible and gains the ability to move through other units until he attacks or uses an ability. If he breaks the invisibility with an attack, that attack will deal bonus damage."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="15">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="15/20/25/30"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="30/60/90/120"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Fade Time"
                value="1/0.75/0.5/0.25"/>
            <altDescription description="The court jesters present during King Goff's assassination can recount no other image than a dancing shadow." />
            <note>Will not break most channeling of spells upon activation.</note>
            <note>The bonus damage is dealt as a separate non-crittable damage instance.</note>
            <note>Invisibility is broken as soon as you start an attack, or start casting any spell.</note>
            <note>Items and abilities used during the fade time will not stop Bounty Hunter from going invisible.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Track"
            description="Tracks an enemy hero and grants a gain in movement speed to allies near the hunted. If the target dies, Bounty Hunter and nearby heroes collect a bounty in gold."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemy Heroes"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            mantaStyle="2"
            cooldown="10/7/5"
            mana="50">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="900/1050/1200"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Speed Radius"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="30"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="20%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Gold for Self"
                value="150/200/250"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Gold for Allies"
                value="50/100/150"/>
            <altDescription description="Using his elevated senses of sight and smell, Gondar's hits have quite a good chance of success." />
            <note>Bounty Hunter will get the bonus gold if the target dies while the spell is still active, regardless of how it dies.</note>
            <note>Gives True Sight of the target.</note>
            <note>Bonus gold will be added as reliable gold.</note>
            <note>Can be used to illusions.</note>
            <note>The track animation is hidden from enemies, although they can see the debuff on their status bar and the animation on nearby enemy units.</note>
            <note>Allies will only gain bonus gold if they are within 900 radius of the tracked target.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Track provides a great deal of benefits to the team, the vision and movement speed help with ganking enemies as well as with avoiding enemy ganks, and the bonus gold will provide a big advantage over the enemy team if you get kills. You should try to cast it on every enemy hero, though priority targets should be carries as well as those that can go invisible.</tips>
        <tips>Despite being classified a carry, Bounty Hunter is also a strong ganker. Your abilities give you a great deal of power in the mid game, you should use this time to gank enemies as the bonus gold from Track more than makes up for the farm you may miss.</tips>
        <tips>Although it provides a great deal of benefits, Battle Fury is not always the best item to get since its main purpose is to farm. It may be better to opt for an Orchid Malevolence, Medallion of Courage, or other such items that will help you gank better early on.</tips>
        <tips>Although not always recommended, Shadow Blade can be useful for damage stacking. Using it and quickly Shadow Walking will give you +270 on your next attack, combining that with Jinada can heavily wound an enemy.</tips>
        <tips>It is possible to get the bonus damage of Shadow Walk twice by attacking once during the fade time and once to break the invisibility. This can help securing last hits or harassing.</tips>
        <tips>Getting an Orb of Venom is an extremely effective item when ganking in the early phase of the game as the 12% slow together with the slow from Jinada can make your opponent much easier to kill.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Brewmaster</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.9"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="1.95"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="1.25"
            damageMinimum="52"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="4.14" />
        <ability
            name="Thunder Clap"
            description="Slams the ground, dealing damage and slowing the movement speed and attack rate of nearby enemy land units."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="12"
            mana="90/105/130/150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="400"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Attack Speed Slow"
                value="25/35/45/55"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Slow"
                value="25%/35%/45%/55%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100/175/250/300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="4.25 on Heroes (8 on creeps)"/>
            <altDescription description="A slam of Mangix' mighty keg starts the festivities." />
            <note>Given to Earth when holding Aghanim's Scepter, at the same level as the original Brewmaster.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Drunken Haze"
            description="Drenches a small area in alcohol, causing their movement speed to be reduced, and causing their attacks to have a chance to miss."
            ability="Target Units"
            affects="Enemies"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="8"
            mana="50">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="850"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="200"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="8 on Heroes (12 on creeps)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Slow"
                value="14%/18%/22%/26%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Miss Chance"
                value="45%/55%/65%/75%"/>
            <altDescription description="The Order of the Oyo's solution to all problems - another round!" />
            <note>Drunken Haze cannot be disjointed.</note>
            <note>Affects a 200 AoE around the target.</note>
            <note>Given to Storm when holding Aghanim's Scepter, at the same level as the original Brewmaster.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Drunken Brawler"
            description="Gives a chance to avoid attacks and to deal critical damage."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Dodge Chance"
                value="10%/15%/20%/25%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Critical Chance"
                value="10%/15%/20%/25%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Critical Damage"
                value="2x"/>
            <mantaStyle description="Red critical numbers are before illusion and armor reduction." />
            <altDescription description="When Mangix won his title as the Brewmaster of the Order of Oyo, he also claimed his place in the mastery of inebriation." />
            <note>Stacks with evasion from items diminishingly.</note>
            <note>Given to Fire when holding Aghanim's Scepter, at the same level as the original Brewmaster.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Primal Split"
            description="Splits the Brewmaster into elements, forming 3 specialized warriors, adept at survival. If any of them survive until the end of their summoned timer, the Brewmaster is reborn. Upgradable by Aghanim's Scepter."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="140/120/100"
            mana="125/150/175">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="15/17/19"/>
            <aghanims description="Gives Thunder Clap to Earth, Drunken Haze to Storm, and Drunken Brawler to Fire, at the same level as the original Brewmaster and with independent cooldowns from the original Brewmaster." />
            <altDescription description="It isn't clear whether Mangix is consciously aware of his potent bond with nature, as it often occurs in the midst of a drunken stupor." />
            <note>When the spell ends, the Brewmaster takes Earth's place. If Earth is dead he takes Storm's place, and if Storm is dead he takes Fire's place.</note>
            <note>All of the warriors possess the Resistant Skin passive ability. Skills that have separate effects for heroes and creeps (such as Enchantress' Enchant) will use the Hero effects when targeting the warriors. Skills that affect only creeps (such as Doom Bringer's Devour) or only Heroes (such as Witch Doctor's Death Ward) will not affect the warriors.</note>
            <note>Warriors are not considered summons. Thus, it does not take summon bonus damage.</note>
            <note>The Earth warrior has every aura of the Brewmaster (Such as Vladmir's Offering or Assault Cuirass). If the Earth warrior dies, the auras will move to Storm, then Fire. This is true for all items with an area of effect (such as Gem or Drum of Endurance).</note>
            <note>The Warriors are affected by Enigma's Black Hole.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Hurl Boulder"
            description="Throws a boulder at a unit, doing damage and stunning it."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="7"
            mana="100">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="800"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="2"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100"/>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Spell Immunity"
            description="Immune to spells."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self">
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Pulverize"
            description="Provides a chance to do damage in a small radius."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="150/250"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="40/20"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Chance"
                value="20%"/>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Dispel Magic"
            description="Damages summoned units in a small radius and purges most buffs or debuffs."
            ability="Target Area"
            affects="Units"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="8"
            mana="75">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Area"
                value="200"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage to summons"
                value="200"/>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Cyclone"
            description="Encloses a unit in a tornado, removing it from the battlefield."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemy Units"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="8"
            mana="150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="6 on heroes (20 on creeps)"/>
            <note>Warlock Golem is disabled for 6 seconds as it's a hero summons.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Wind Walk"
            description="Provides temporary invisibility. Bonus movement speed and attack damage when invisible."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="7"
            mana="75">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="20"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="100"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="50%"/>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Permanent Immolation"
            description="Burns nearby enemy units."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage per Second"
                value="15/30/45"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Area"
                value="220"/>
        </ability>
        <tips>Brewmaster is strong against auto-attack heroes; Thunder Clap slows down attack speed, Drunken Haze causes them to miss, and Drunken Brawler helps him dodge attacks and deal critical damage.</tips>
        <tips>Thunder Clap is extremely strong at the early stages of the game, acting as his area-of-effect cripple. It is generally leveled up first.</tips>
        <tips>Neither Drunken Haze nor Drunken Brawler are exceptionally useful at levels 2 and 4, so it is not uncommon to opt for stats instead.</tips>
        <tips>Against extremely strong physical harassment (such as Sniper or Weaver), consider going for a Drunken Haze and Drunken Brawler build to maximize your dodge chance.</tips>
        <tips>Although Phase Boots are recommended, many opt for Arcane Boots instead if the hero is being played in a ganking or initiator role, as it can allow you to use Thunder Clap and Primal Split in succession much earlier and solve mana issues.</tips>
        <tips>Use Primal Split sparingly, as it has an extremely long cooldown. Try to avoid using it to run away if at all possible.</tips>
        <tips>If Brewmaster is being played more in the semi-carry role, consider using his ultimate as a life saver to keep yourself in the fight when you would normally die. The utility of the Brewlings works excellently for finishing off opponents as well as initiation.</tips>
q        <tips>When playing Brewmaster, try to gain an advantage for your team early before anybody on the enemy carry can build a Black King Bar. Against magic immunity, both his anti-carry abilities and Primal Split abilities are rendered useless and must be focused on another target.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Bristleback</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Rigwarl the Bristleback is a melee Strength hero famous for his array of synergistic spells with low mana cost and cooldown. He is able to slow his enemies down and reduce their armor with Viscous Nasal Goo, then hit them with a barrage of Quill Sprays, making him an effective chaser when ganking enemies. His low strength gain makes him less tanky than most strength heroes, but he becomes substantially more durable when he turns around due to his passive Bristleback, which reduces damage taken from behind. In the right hands, Bristleback is a powerful ganker in the early stages of the game, and a powerful hard carry in the later stages depending on how much farm he gets.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.2"
            agilityBase="17"
            agilityGain="1.8"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="2.8"
            damageMinimum="48"
            damageMaximum="58"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="3.43" />
        <ability
            name="Vicious Nasal Goo"
            description="Covers a target in snot, causing it to have reduced armor and movement speed. Multiple casts stack and refresh the duration."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="1.5"
            mana="30">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Armor Reduction"
                value="1/1/2/2"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Reduction per Cast"
                value="20% and +3%/+6%/+9%/+12%"/>
            <altDescription description="Having caught a cold while stuck in the snow, Bristleback turns it to his advantage." />
            <note>Stacks a maximum of 4 times, meaning it can at most reduce armor by 4/4/8/8 and movement speed by 32/44/56/68%.</note>
            <note>Stacks are immediately removed if the unit becomes Magic Immune.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Quill Spray"
            description="Sprays enemy units with quills dealing damage in an area of effect around Bristleback. Deals bonus damage for every time a unit was hit by Quill Spray in the last 14 seconds."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Physical"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="3"
            mana="35">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="625"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="14"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Damage"
                value="20/40/60/80"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stack Damage"
                value="30"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Cap"
                value="400"/>
            <altDescription description="An enforcer's honor can be a prickly thing. So can his quills." />
            <note>Quill Spray damage is not reduced by damage block abilities. (such as Vanguard, Kraken Shell.)</note>
            <note>Stacks are independent, not refreshing, which means that normally Bristleback can deal at most (14s duration / 3s cooldown) 120 bonus damage. To reach the damage cap you need additional Quill Sprays from Bristleback passive.</note>
            <note>The stacks cannot be removed by Purge or other buff removing abilities such as Kraken Shell.</note>
            <note>13/12/12/11 stacks are required to reach the 400 damage cap, which so require 9/8/8/7 sprays from Bristleback (which takes 2500/2250/2250/2000 damage taken from the rear), since only 4 stacks can be achieved with Quill Spray alone.</note>
            <note>Has an instant cast time.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Bristleback"
            description="Bristleback takes less damage if hit on the sides or rear. If Bristleback takes 250 damage from the rear, he releases a Quill Spray of the current level."
            ability="Passive"
            mantaStyle="1">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Reduced Damage (Rear)"
                value="16%/24%/32%/40%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Reduced Damage (Side)"
                value="8%/12%/16%/20%"/>
            <mantaStyle description="Illusions benefit damage reduction, but not quill spray procs." />
            <altDescription description="Turning his back to a fight might be just the thing." />
            <note>Bristleback's rear is considered to be within 70 degrees from the back.</note>
            <note>Bristleback's side is considered to be within 110 degrees from the back.</note>
            <note>Bristleback takes less damage from all damage types except HP removal.</note>
            <note>Damage reduction (and Quill Spray triggers) are calculated by comparing the location of the damage instance's source to Bristleback's orientation. This applies to damage over time ticks as well.</note>
            <note>The amount of damage considered towards buff removal proc is the one actually done to Rigwarl, and is reset after a passive Quill Spray from Bristleback occurs.</note>
            <note>Passive Quill Spray proc does not cost mana.</note>
            <note>Bristleback does not work against towers.</note>
            <note>Ability is disabled by Doom, Chronosphere, Hexes.</note>
            <note>Animation shows Quill Spray procs even if the Quill Spray is not learnt, but it does not damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Warpath"
            description="Bristleback works himself up into a fury every time he casts a spell, increasing his movement speed and damage. The first stack (base) provides larger bonuses."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="14"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="8%/12%/16%/20%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Bonus Damage"
                value="20/25/30"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stack Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="1%/2%/3%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stack Bonus Damage"
                value="20/25/30"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Max Stacks"
                value="5/6/7"/>
            <altDescription description="'Temper, temper,' his mum always chided. But in a fight, a temper can come in handy." />
            <note>Bristleback's Illusions will receive the bonuses.</note>
            <note>Stacks up to 5/6/7 times, meaning it can give at most 9/17/28% movement speed and 100/150/210 attack damage.</note>
            <note>Using items does not trigger Warpath.</note>
            <note>Gaining a stack of Warpath does not refresh the duration of previous stacks, i.e. each stack has its own duration.</note>
            <note>Quill Spray triggers from Bristleback do not trigger Warpath.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Use your passive skill Bristleback to your advantage; anticipate enemy attacks and turn your back on them, so that you can reduce as much damage as you can.</tips>
        <tips>An early skill point on this skill during the laning phase can help you stay in the lane a while longer, especially if you are having trouble against auto-attacks.</tips>
        <tips>Even if your enemies can easily defend against you with a Magic Wand, you can still heavily damage them with Warpath; as long as you're stacking your spells against them, the bonus damage will do its job.</tips>
        <tips>Viscous Nasal Goo is an extremely useful cripple, provided that you keep casting it against your target, as it slows their movement speed for 32/44/56/68%. The cripple's duration is up to you, since you can continuously cast it to refresh the duration, and its cooldown is only 1.5 seconds. However, this ability has a significant backswing, so when you're chasing, be sure to issue a walk or attack command immediately after you see the snot come out.</tips>
        <tips>This skill is very effective when combined with Warlock's Fatal Bonds, as the damage inflicted on the crippled target from other bound creeps or heroes is applied to the armor reduced hero at said reduced value. This makes the Bristleback/Warlock lane combination very potent, even into the late game. When combined with area of effect items and attacks, a lot of damage can be dealt very quickly.</tips>
        <tips>Bristleback's mana woes can easily be remedied by a Sage's Mask or a Ring of Basilius, since his skills have extremely low mana costs.</tips>
        <tips>One of Bristleback's main weaknesses is his lack of disables, meaning he cannot silence or interrupt an enemy from casting spells. You can either rely on your teammates for disables, or create an item of your own, so long as it benefits him in some way (a good example would be a Scythe of Vyse, since it gives him good mana regeneration for his skills, and a devastating hex disable).</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Broodmother</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <tips>Black Arachnia the Broodmother is a melee agility hero who is a notably powerful pusher. Her trademark spiderlings, as both an asset and a liability, define her play style. While a possible additional source of income, experience and lane pushes, spiderlings can easily feed opponents when not handled with deft micro and great awareness. Broodmother's abilities allow her to summon those spiderlings to do her bidding, to conceal herself and her spiderlings in an area, and to slow and kill heroes with relative ease if caught off guard, all while staying as elusive as possible with her webs and passives. She spends most of the early game pressuring a lane with little concern, due to her spiderlings and her invisibility/added HP regeneration, but she can also transition into a difficult to kill melee carry, which can dive in on and rapidly kill lone enemies with the right items later on.</tips>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.5"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="2.2"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="2.0"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="50"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="2.57" />
        <ability
            name="Spawn Spiderlings"
            description="Broodmother injects her young into an enemy unit, dealing damage. The spiderlings will hatch if the target is killed while under this influence."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            cooldown="10"
            mana="120">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="700"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="75/150/225/300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Count"
                value="1/2/3/4"/>
            <altDescription description="Black Arachnia continues to raise her young, even amidst the field of combat. The brood quickly learns how to support their mother." />
            <note>Units from which the Spiderlings spawn leave no corpse on death.</note>
            <note>If the target is killed within 2 seconds of being hit by this skill, regardless of what the killer is, the Spiderlings will spawn (This includes denying an "infected" ally or committing suicide).</note>
            <note>Units killed by Spiderlings will then give birth to Spiderites, smaller and less powerful versions of the Spiderlings.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Spin Web"
            description="Throws out a web that renders Broodmother invisible in its vicinity, while also boosting regeneration, and granting a passive movement speed increase."
            ability="Target Point"
            mantaStyle="0"
            cooldown="30"
            mana="50">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="1000"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Maximum Webs"
                value="2/4/6/8"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Health Regeneration"
                value="2/4/6/8"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="20%/25%/30%/35%"/>
            <altDescription description="Weaving a bed of silken fibers, Arachnia's web both protects her and her offspring, as well as giving advancing opponents a sense of foreboding." />
            <note>Has an invisibility fade time of 2 seconds, but invisibility is instantly lost outside the web.</note>
            <note>Movement speed and health regeneration are instantly granted and lost when moving in or out of the web.</note>
            <note>Also affects Spiderlings and Spiderites.</note>
            <note>If more webs are spawned than allowed, the oldest one will disappear.</note>
            <note>Webs are marked by icons on the minimap.</note>
            <note>If no enemy has vision over Broodmother, she gains unobstructed movement within the web (can walk over cliffs, trees, etc) with no collision box.</note>
            <note>Spiderlings and Spiderites do not get unobstructed movement; however, they get their collision box removed.</note>
            <note>Has a 0.4 cast point (slower than default).</note>
            <note>Broodmother will not be able to become invisible while muted, but will not lose her invisibility if she is already on a web. Other components behave normally.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Incapacitating Bite"
            description="Broodmother's venom cripples enemy units, causing her attacks to slow, as well as giving the affected unit a chance to miss its attacks. Incapacitating Bite is a Unique Attack Modifier, and does not stack with other Unique Attack Modifiers."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Enemies"
            orbOfVenom="1"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="2"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Miss Chance"
                value="30%/40%/50%/60%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Move Slow"
                value="10%/20%/30%/40%"/>
            <altDescription description="Paralytic toxins come from Black Arachnia's fangs, causing a slow and painful death to those who intrude on her webs." />
            <note>The affected enemies' miss chance stacks with evasion and terrain dodge chance.</note>
            <note>In DotA 1, this ability is blocked by Linken's Sphere. The change appears to be intended.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Insatiable Hunger"
            description="A violent lust for vital fluids increases Broodmother's attack damage and gives her a vampiric attack."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="45"
            mana="100">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="60/80/100"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Lifesteal"
                value="40%/60%/80%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="14"/>
            <altDescription description="While most of her prey is wrapped in silken cocoons and saved for her young, the Broodmother herself has a taste for wandering heroes." />
            <note>Fully stacks with all items providing lifesteal (both Unique Attack Modifiers and auras).</note>
            <note>Can only be removed by Purge (from Diffusal Blade, Stone Gaze, Demonic Purge, Unstable Current, or the Satyr Trickster).</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Spin Web and Spawn Spiderlings should almost always be maxed first, before points are put into any other ability. Both Incapacitating Bite and Insatiable Hunger are only useful once Broodmother has gotten her farm.</tips>
        <tips>Going into a solo lane is a viable option for Broodmother as webs give her the survivability and the pushing power from the spiderlings can overwhelm a lane without need of her being babysat by an additional hero.</tips>
        <tips>Spawn Spiderlings acts as a ranged nuke, and is very useful for killing weak enemies that are fleeing.</tips>
        <tips>Soul Ring is a great item to have on her as the instant mana boost gives her the ability to spawn more spiderlings and the HP regen from the webs can cover for the loss of HP from the Soul ring.</tips>
        <tips>Going right into a Black King Bar is a good choice as the combination of magic immunity and the powerful lifesteal from Insatiable Hunger makes the Broodmother a very difficult opponent to kill.</tips>
        <tips>Casting Spin Web on top of an enemy tower makes it easy to dive in on weak heroes. The regen and movespeed bonus combined with Broodmother's slow is very effective for diving on heroes with no reliable escape or stun.</tips>
        <tips>Broodmother is very effective against solitary targets, but against multiple enemies she suffers; as her lifesteal can generally only replenish the damage taken from a solitary foe.</tips>
        <tips>A quick Yasha will give her more movement speed to evade ganks and remain a threat for that lane. Then this can be made into a Manta Style which will give her a way to remove dust and confuse the enemy to escape ganks and waste their crowd control spells.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Centaur Warrunner</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Bradwarden the Centaur Warrunner is a melee strength hero whose natural place in combat is right in the center of battle. His abilities stop enemies around him in their tracks and inflict heavy damage, making him an excellent initiator. He is also a powerful tank, having the highest strength gain in the game. Bradwarden has immense natural health, and his skills' area of effect mean that he can charge into combat and incapacitate groups of enemies at a time. Hoof Stomp and Double Edge make a great combo of stunning and burst damage on short cooldowns and his Return means instant retaliation on enemies who try attack him. His ultimate, Stampede effectively turns the entire team into initiators, granting them high speed and the ability to flatten enemies under as they pass over them. Although he is usually not played as a carry, he can scale powerfully with items, becoming a hard-hitting semi-carry that is nearly impossible to kill.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="3.8"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="2.0"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.6"
            damageMinimum="55"
            damageMaximum="57"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="3.14" />
        <ability
            name="Hoof Stomp"
            description="Slams the ground, stunning and damaging nearby enemy units."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="13"
            mana="85/100/115/130">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="315"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stun Duration"
                value="2/2.25/2.5/2.75"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100/150/200/250"/>
            <altDescription description="When the mighty hoof of the Warrunner touches soil, the tremors are felt far and wide." />
            <note>Can hit invisible units.</note>
            <note>Has a small cast delay.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Double Edge"
            description="Centaur strikes a mighty blow at melee range, damaging both himself and the target. Centaur cannot die from Double Edge. Double Edge deals its damage in a 190 AoE around the target."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="8">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="150"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="190"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="175/250/325/400"/>
            <linkensSphere description="Bradwarden doesn't takes his recoil damage if blocked." />
            <altDescription description="In the spurs of combat, Bradwarden's vicious strikes sometimes cause self-inflicted collateral damage." />
            <note>Double Edge deals magic type damage to both the targets and himself.</note>
            <note>Double Edge can be used to commit suicide, but only if Centaur Warrunner is under the effect of damage amplification.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Return"
            description="Centaur Warrunner immediately counters every attack, damaging the attacker based on a percentage of Centaur's strength."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Enemy Units and Structures"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Base Damage"
                value="16/18/20/22"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage as Percent of Centaur Warrunner's Strength"
                value="26%/34%/42%/50%"/>
            <altDescription description="Bradwarden has no need to parry his opponent's attacks; his armor-like hide does it for him." />
            <note>This ability works on towers.</note>
            <note>Return causes damage when the enemy begins a normal attack, not when their attack hits.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Stampede"
            description="Centaur leads all allies into a vicious charge causing them to move through units at max speed and slow enemy units they tread upon. Each enemy can be trampled once and takes damage based on the Warrunner's strength."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Allies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="90/75/60"
            mana="80">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Charge Duration"
                value="3.75"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="1/2/3 times your strength"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Slow"
                value="100%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Slow Duration"
                value="1.5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stampede Collision Radius"
                value="105"/>
            <altDescription description="The great belt of Omexe, which labels Bradwarden as the greatest warrior of his kind, incites his fellow gladiators to follow him into barbarous combat." />
            <note>Units hit by Stampede cannot have their movement speed reduced below 100.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>When trying to land Hoof Stomp on fleeing enemies, get in front of their path if possible. Most opponents will outrun the stun during the cast-time if they are already on the edge of the AoE.</tips>
        <tips>Return is an extremely powerful ability and not to be underestimated. Although its most notable effect is greatly increasing damage against enemies that try to gank Warrunner in the late game, even at lower levels it can completely shut down heroes with high damage and low health.</tips>
        <tips>To force a tower to attack you and utilize Return, issue an attack command upon an enemy hero when in range (even one in another lane).</tips>
        <tips>This trick also works to aggravate lane creeps.</tips>
        <tips>You can use Stampede's movement speed boost to help allies escape or chase in a pinch, although the long cooldown makes this usage situational.</tips>
        <tips>Stampede gives all allies the power to become initiators, allowing the entire team the chance to break into battle with destructive force; unfortunately, Stampede only affects enemies once for a relatively short duration, so in larger fights the skill may go totally awry. This means the initiation must be careful and planned, with a chosen initiator, as with other fights (more than not, possibly Warrunner himself).</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Chaos Knight</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Chaos Knight is a melee strength Hero with one of the highest physical damage outputs of all heroes. He is mostly played as a semi-carry and ganker. As his name implies, he has a theme based on randomness and uncertainty. His regular attack has an incredibly high thirty damage spread, making his last hitting ability somewhat unreliable. Chaos Bolt is his most notorious luck-based ability which, at max level, can stun a target anywhere between a mediocre 2 seconds to an effective 4 seconds that will almost certainly assure its death; it will also deal a variable amount of damage ranging from miniscule to moderate. Reality Rift pulls Chaos Knight and his target to a randomly chosen point along the line between the two and gives him bonus damage for one attack. Chaos Strike is a crit-based ability with one of the lowest proc chances, yet also one of the highest multipliers. His only non-random ability is his ultimate Phantasm, which produces the most powerful illusions in the game. These illusions, which retain his full damage and only take double damage, benefit from his Chaos Strike and can teleport alongside him to attack the target whenever he uses Reality Rift. With three illusions being produced at Phantasm's highest level, Chaos Knight's damage output is effectively quadrupled during teamfights later in the game, and it is not uncommon to see enemy heroes being killed instantly after being Reality Rifted by the four apocalyptic horsemen. Thus, CK is played as a carry whom excels in both the mid and late game, if the game drags on long enough and he is able to acquire enough strength-based and survivability items to ensure that his illusions can stay alive, he will be able to overpower most hard carries.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="20"
            strengthGain="2.9"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="2.1"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.2"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="79"
            baseMoveSpeed="325"
            baseArmor="4.0" />
        <ability
            name="Chaos Bolt"
            description="Throws a mysterious bolt of energy at the target unit. It stuns for a random duration and deals random damage."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="10"
            mana="140">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Min Stun Duration"
                value="1/1/1/2"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Max Stun Duration"
                value="2/3/4/4"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Min Damage"
                value="1/50/75/100"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Max Damage"
                value="200/225/250/275"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Projectile Speed"
                value="1000"/>
            <altDescription description="Bradwarden has no need to parry his opponent's attacks; his armor-like hide does it for him." />
            <note>Stun duration and damage appears above targeted unit's head (visible to allies and enemies).</note>
            <note>Damage and stun values are inversely related.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Reality Rift"
            description="Teleports you, any images you have and the target unit to a random point along the line between the two of you. Gives you bonus attack damage for one attack."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            mantaStyle="1"
            cooldown="24/18/12/6"
            mana="70">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="550/600/650/700"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="25/50/75/100"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Duration"
                value="1.2"/>
            <mantaStyle description="Illusions belonging to Chaos Knight within a range of 1400 will be teleported to the same position as the original. Illusions will not gain the bonus damage." />
            <altDescription description="Armageddon rides between the planes, bringing Chaos Knight to his victim wherever he may hide." />
            <note>Chaos Knight and the target unit are made to face each other, and Chaos Knight and his illusions are issued an attack order against the target.</note>
            <note>Teleports Chaos Knight to a random point on the line between the units (between 30% and 80% of the distance).</note>
            <note>Teleports the target unit to the same location as Chaos Knight, offset by 25 units towards Chaos Knight's original position.</note>
            <note>Illusions will not gain the bonus damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Chaos Strike"
            description="Chaos Knight's mojo gives him a chance to deal bonus damage."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Critical Chance"
                value="10%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Critical Damage"
                value="1.5x/2x/2.5x/3x"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Duration"
                value="1.2"/>
            <mantaStyle description="Red critical numbers are before illusion and armor reduction." />
            <altDescription description="Chaos Knight's unwieldy power bludgeons those who stand before him, crushing the thickest of armors." />
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Phantasm"
            description="Summons several copies of the Chaos Knight from alternate dimensions. The illusions deal full damage, but take double damage."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="140"
            mana="125/200/275">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="24"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Number of Illusions"
                value="1/2/3"/>
            <altDescription description="Drawing on his battles fought across many worlds and many times, phantasms of the Chaos Knight rise up to quell all who oppose him." />
            <note>This ability removes most buffs from Chaos Knight.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>While ganking in the early-mid game, use Reality Rift to get close to the enemy, then hit him once with your bonus damage and use Chaos Bolt to stun. If you're lucky, you could even get more than 2 hits while he's stunned.</tips>
        <tips>In most situations, max Chaos Bolt and Reality Rift first, since the critical damage from your Chaos Strike is negligible in the early game, and you won't have enough mana to summon the Phantasm(s) with your ultimate.</tips>
        <tips>Always activate your Armlet of Mordiggian before using your ultimate, since the illusions also gain bonuses from it.</tips>
        <tips>By buying a Sange &amp; Yasha, you'll be able to disassemble it later and build a Heaven's Halberd and a Manta Style. You may buy the first item if you need more survivability, since it gives you more health, some evasion and a reliable disarm; buy Manta Style first if you farmed really well, and you wish to confuse your enemies even more. It also grants additional stats.</tips>
        <tips>Diffusal Blade will give Chaos Knight's illusions Feedback. Like Phantom Lancer, an army of Chaos Knights can deplete enemy's mana very quickly. Its active ability can also be used to ensure that enemies do not escape Chaos Knight's army after Reality Rift, if Chaos Bolt is unavailable.</tips>
        <tips>Buying an early Soul Ring will solve most of Chaos Knight's mana problems.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Chen</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Chen the Holy Knight has gameplay that is different than most other heroes. Holy Persuasion lets him convert creeps to his side, including powerful neutral creeps. As a result, Chen is usually found in the forest searching for creeps to convert. When he finds a strong creep or two, he descends on his unwary enemies, using both his own spells and the abilities of his persuaded creeps to take them out. When ambushing enemies, Chen generally uses his Penitence ability, which slows the target and causes them to take extra damage from Chen's flock. Test of Faith can be used to finish off enemies and also teleport any ally to the fountain after a short delay with a subability. Chen's support abilities are rounded out by Hand of God, a healing spell which instantly restores a set amount of HP to all allied Heroes and fully heals his controlled creeps across the battlefield.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Jungler</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="20"
            strengthGain="1.5"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="2.1"
            intelligenceBase="21"
            intelligenceGain="2.8"
            damageMinimum="43"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
        <ability
            name="Penitence"
            description="Forces an enemy unit to move slower and take more damage from attacks and spells."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="14"
            mana="100">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="7"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Slow"
                value="8%/16%/24%/32%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="8%/16%/24%/32%"/>
            <altDescription description="Although Chen's brand of animal enthrallment isn't quite strong enough to control the minds of enemy heroes, it still tests their resolve in combat." />
            <note>Damage is considered a separate instance of damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Test of Faith"
            description="Deals random damage to test an enemy unit's faith."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Pure"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            cooldown="24"
            mana="175">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Min"
                value="50/100/150/200"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Max"
                value="100/200/300/400"/>
            <altDescription description="Knights of the Fold possess a fanatical form of magic that is considered quite unwieldy by most other users of arcane arts." />
            <note>Despite being two parts of the same ability, Test of Faith and the Teleport component don't share cooldown.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Test of Faith (Teleport)"
            description="Teleports a friendly unit back to the base. Creeps are teleported instantly, Heroes have a delay before teleporting."
            ability="Target Unit"
            blackKingBar="0"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="24"
            mana="200">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Hero Teleport Delay"
                value="6/5/4/3"/>
            <diffusalBlade description="Can be dispelled on heroes during the delay." />
            <note>Despite being two parts of the same ability, Test of Faith and the Teleport component don't share cooldown.</note>
            <note>Using on a friendly Pudge while he's hooking an enemy used to drag them all the way to the fountain, killing them nigh instantly. This was fixed in The First Blood Update.</note>
            <note>Under certain circumstances, Sand King won't be teleported back to the base while using Burrowstrike.</note>
            <note>If dispelled, the hero will not be brought back to base.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Holy Persuasion"
            description="Gives control of an enemy or neutral creep, and gives it bonus hit points."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Creeps"
            blackKingBar="2"
            cooldown="30/26/22/18"
            mana="100">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Max Units"
                value="1/1/2/3"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Health Bonus"
                value="75/150/225/300"/>
            <altDescription description="Although they may not be knights, Chen incorporates beasts into the Fold in the same way he himself was converted." />
            <note>You can take control of only non-Ancient type creeps.</note>
            <note>When persuading a new creep above your max unit count, the oldest persuaded unit will die.</note>
            <note>With the help of Rubick, a creep can be infinitely juggled, thus every time the creep is converted it gains more maximum health.</note>
            <note>If an enemy has dominated a creep with the item Helm of the Dominator, you can use Holy Persuasion on it, thus gaining control over it.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Hand of God"
            description="Fully regenerates any creeps under Chen's control and heals all allied heroes on the map."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Allies"
            cooldown="160/140/120 (30*)"
            mana="200/300/400">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Health"
                value="200/300/400"/>
            <aghanims description="Reduces cooldown." />
            <altDescription description="Using the mental link with his thralls, Chen calls down restoration and well-being to those who share his fanaticism." />
            <note>Heals magic immune units.</note>
            <note>Global.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>You should try to end the game as soon as possible, because Chen's effectiveness diminishes as the game progresses.</tips>
        <tips>Chen is a good jungler and can take any camp at level 1 if you skill Holy Persuasion.</tips>
        <tips>While jungling, don't be too selective about the creeps. Just persuade the higher level ones in the large creep camps and persuade new creeps if yours are on low HP.</tips>
        <tips>Try to keep your creeps group in a Hotkey of some sort (Command groups, tabbing, selecting all other units) and also have another hotkey for both creeps and Chen.</tips>
        <tips>Always try to send in your creeps while keeping Chen at a safe distance (don't send him in the middle of a battle with your creeps) and keep an eye on him and his hp while controlling the creeps.</tips>
        <tips>Always try to keep an eye on the minimap in case you have to use Hand of God to heal a teammate.</tips>
        <tips>Try always to have enough mana to use Hand of God when it isn't on cooldown, as it may be needed at any time.</tips>
        <tips>For jungling, it's useful to have a Satyr Tormentor, as it makes your creeps regenerate HP faster and can use an AoE spell.</tips>
        <tips>For ganking, it's very useful to have at least a Centaur Conqueror / Hellbear Smasher (for the stomp stun/slow) and a Dark Troll Summoner (for the Ensnare so the centaur can get positioned).</tips>
        <tips>You can have guaranteed ganks at level 1 or 2 if you get either a Centaur Khan or an Ursa Warrior and your ally has a stun or a slow.</tips>
        <tips>For pushing, it's very useful to have either Satyr Tormentors (with their nuke they take down creep waves easily), an Wildwing Ripper (its Tornado takes down creeps fast) or even Centaur Conquerors (they are tanky).</tips>
        <tips>For team battles, Centaur Conquerers are the best option, as they can keep the enemies stunned for up to 6 seconds.</tips>
        <tips>In team battles, try to use your Mekansm (if you have it) before Hand of God as it gives an armor boost too.</tips>
        <tips>Try to use either Mekansm or Hand of God when all your allies are damaged to maximize the healing, rather than just healing a damaged ally while the rest are with full hp.</tips>
        <tips>Try to kill Roshan around level 6-7 since your creeps can tank it very well and you can instant heal them with your ultimate.</tips>
        <tips>If the game keeps going on until late game (which you should avoid and try to finish the game fast) you should persuade an Alpha Wolf, and make it follow your carry, as it will greatly increase his/her damage dealt.</tips>
        <tips>Be especially wary of Doom, Lifestealer, Enchantress and Clinkz as they can take away your creeps instantly and with the help of a Hand of Midas two of your creeps can be destroyed before they even get near the enemy. Clinkz is a special mention as due to the fact that the creeps Chen persuades have increased HP Clinkz not only gets a huge HP boost from consuming your creeps but also a large damage boost on top of it using his ultimate. The same can be said about Naix if he is not properly locked down as he can use the increased HP of your creeps to not only Infest your creeps to heal himself on the spot but also deal nuke damage back to you and all of your allies present. Doom and Enchantress on the other hand while incapable of healing themselves using your creep can instead use the abilities of your own creeps against you as Doom's Devour skill grants him the skills of the creep he consumes while Enchantress' enchant simply takes the creep from under your control.</tips>
        <tips>Also be wary if the enemy team has an Ancient Apparition as Ice Blast prevents your ultimate ability from healing the affected units.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Clinkz</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Clinkz, the Bone Fletcher is a ranged agility carry specializing in ambushing lone Heroes with high physical damage and incredible speed. Though frail and easy to kill, Skeleton Walk grants Clinkz stealth and haste to escape and re-position himself. This assassin Strafes around the enemy, launching a flurry of Searing Arrows that greatly injure enemies. To aid his assault, Clinkz can form a Death Pact and absorb a creature's life for greater damage and health, making him not only able to take more hits, but hit harder as well.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="15"
            strengthGain="1.6"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="3.0"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.55"
            damageMinimum="37"
            damageMaximum="43"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="2.14" />
        <ability
            name="Strafe"
            description="Clinkz attacks with a barrage of arrows. Dramatically increases attack speed for a short time."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="45/40/35/30"
            mana="90">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="4/6/8/10"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Attack Speed"
                value="130"/>
            <altDescription description="It's hard to say whether the blur around the Bone Fletcher is from his flaming heart or his speed with the quiver." />
            <note>Clinkz will get an animation on him for the duration of the spell, showing that it's currently active.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Searing Arrows"
            description="Imbues Clinkz's arrows with fire for extra damage."
            ability="Auto-Cast"
            affects="Enemy Units and Structures"
            damage="Physical"
            orbOfVenom="1"
            mana="10">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="30/40/50/60"/>
            <altDescription description="Clinkz simply lights his arrows from his flaming essence for quite the destructive effect." />
            <note>Searing Arrows will stack with Eye of Skadi if it is Auto-Cast, but not if it is manually cast. The same goes for triggering Critical Strike.</note>
            <note>Works on mechanical units, such as towers and siege units.</note>
            <note>Works on magic immune units.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Skeleton Walk"
            description="Clinkz moves invisibly through units until the moment he attacks or uses an ability."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Self"
            cooldown="20"
            mana="75">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Fade Time"
                value="0.6"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="20/25/30/35"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="11%/22%/33%/44%"/>
            <altDescription description="With a burst of fire and puff of smoke, the Bone Fletcher was nowhere to be seen." />
            <note>Clinkz can go through units when under the effects of Skeleton Walk.</note>
            <note>Will not interrupt most channeling abilities or items upon activation.</note>
            <note>When attacking, invisibility is broken before the projectile reaches the target.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Death Pact"
            description="Clinkz consumes the target friendly or enemy creep, gaining a percent of its HP as max health and damage."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Units"
            cooldown="45"
            mana="100">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="400"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="35"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus HP Capacity"
                value="50%/65%/80% of killed unit's HP"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Damage"
                value="5%/6.5%/8% of killed unit's HP"/>
            <altDescription description="Sutherex' bond of life and death has become a part of Clinkz, and his old bones are refreshed with repetition of the pact on lesser beings." />
            <note>If the target is an enemy or neutral unit, it will count as a creep kill and give Clinkz the correct gold and experience bounty.</note>
            <note>When the duration ends, the maximum HP returns to normal, but Clinkz's current HP remains the same. If his HP is greater than his normal maximum, it will be set to his maximum.</note>
            <note>It can target a Mud Golem, but not Ancient creeps.</note>
            <note>When used with the neutral jungle creeps with the maximum amount of hp possible of 1100, Clinkz will gain 550/715/880 HP and 55/72/88 Dmg.</note>
            <note>Bonus damage is considered Clinkz's base damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>While he can be an excellent ganker, Clinkz is extremely fragile and puts out huge amounts of DPS, making him a priority target in teamfights. Try to let your teammates start things off while you dance around the edge of the fight dealing damage to distracted or disabled opponents.</tips>
        <tips>You can use orb-walking with Searing Arrows to harass your opponents. Be wary of the moderate mana cost, however.</tips>
        <tips>Use Skeleton Walk a good amount of time before you expect to ambush an enemy, or appear in a fight. This will allow you to use Skeleton Walk again soon after, either for a quick escape or to chase down any survivors.</tips>
        <tips>In most cases, max out Searing Arrows first for the reliable damage increase.</tips>
        <tips>If you are ganking a lot with Clinkz, take Strafe as your second skill to max as the decreased cooldown makes you a great threat. If you are playing as the team's lategame carry, maxing Skeleton Walk will keep you safe and able to move quickly into untaken lanes and the jungle to farm.</tips>
        <tips>Always try to use Death Pact on the bosses of the large creep camps, such as the Satyr Tormenter and Centaur Conqueror.</tips>
        <tips>You can deny an enemy jungler some farm by stealing creeps with Death Pact, leaving as little as possible behind so they are forced to clear it for the respawn to trigger. Death Pact may also be used on dominated or controlled neutrals such as those used by Chen or Enchantress to kill them instantly.</tips>
        <tips>Because of the huge amount of physical damage Clinkz can deal over a short period, he is also excellent at killing towers provided something else is there to take the aggro.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Clockwerk</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Rattletrap the Clockwerk is a melee strength hero commonly played as an initiator or ganker. As an initiator, his main purpose is crowd control. However, he also does secondary jobs such as chasing and map control. His abilities are centered around isolating and killing enemies one by one. He does not deal reliable area damage like most initiators, but still he is capable of doing a surprising and devastating entrance. Usually Clockwerk players should initiate onto low health support heroes or enemy heroes with strong team fight ability, such as Warlock, hampering their ability to land solid teamfight spells. Clockwerk can also initiate onto enemy carry heroes, in order to isolate them away from the team fight by forcing them to remain in cogs.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="24"
            strengthGain="2.7"
            agilityBase="13"
            agilityGain="2.3"
            intelligenceBase="17"
            intelligenceGain="1.3"
            damageMinimum="55"
            damageMaximum="57"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="1.86" />
        <ability
            name="Battery Assault"
            description="Discharges high-powered shrapnel at random nearby enemy units, dealing minor magical damage and ministun."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            mantaStyle="0"
            cooldown="32/28/24/20"
            mana="75">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="275"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="10.5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Interval"
                value="0.7"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="15/35/55/75"/>
            <altDescription description="Some of Rattletrap's contraptions don't quite work correctly, so detonating them proves useful as an offensive maneuver." />
            <note>Remains active even if Clockwerk is disabled.</note>
            <note>Discharges a total of 16 shrapnel.</note>
            <note>Total damage: 240/560/880/1200.</note>
            <note>Does not hit invisible units.</note>
            <note>Mini-stun duration is 0.1 seconds.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Power Cogs"
            description="Forms a barrier of energized cogs around Clockwerk, trapping any units that are near. Enemies outside the trap that touch a cog are knocked back, losing health and mana. Once a cog has delivered a shock, it will power down. Cogs can be destroyed by enemy attacks, but Clockwerk can destroy them with just one."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="15"
            mana="50/60/70/80">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="210"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="5/6/7/8"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Life and Mana Drained"
                value="80/120/160/200"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Enemy Attacks Required"
                value="2/2/2/3"/>
            <altDescription description="One of Clockwerk's inventions of which he is most proud is the power cog - though it is sometimes despised by his allies." />
            <note>Cogs can shock invisible units.</note>
            <note>Enemies that are knocked back are mini-stunned for 0.84 seconds. Damage/Mana drain is done after the mini-stun.</note>
            <note>Knocks back enemies 252 units at a speed of 300 units.</note>
            <note>Cogs give no gold when destroyed.</note>
            <note>Units knocked back will destroy trees in 100 AoE around where they land.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Rocket Flare"
            description="Fires a global range flare that explodes over a given area, damaging enemies and providing vision for 10 seconds."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="20/18/16/14"
            mana="50">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="Global"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="575"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="10"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="80/120/160/200"/>
            <altDescription description="What started as a festive display has become a useful scouting and bombardment tool." />
            <note>Gives vision in a 600 radius.</note>
            <note>The flare travels at a speed of 1500.</note>
            <note>Can block creep camps if timed correctly.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Hookshot"
            description="Fires a grappling device rapidly at the target location. If the hook hits a non-neutral unit, Clockwerk launches himself into the target, stunning and dealing damage. Any enemies Clockwerk collides with along the way are subject to damage and stunned. Upgradable by Aghanim's Scepter."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="70/55/60 (12*)"
            mana="150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="2000/2500/3000"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="125 (175**)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Stun Duration"
                value="1/1.5/2"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100/200/300"/>
            <blackKingBar description="Damage is blocked, stun is not." />
            <aghanims description="Decreases cooldown." />
            <altDescription description="A somewhat unwieldy device, the Hookshot sends the otherwise clunky Clockwerk armor flying through the air." />
            <note>(**) Latch/stun radius</note>
            <note>Magic immunity will block damage, but not the latch or stun.</note>
            <note>Will latch on to and travel to allied units, but will not damage or stun them.</note>
            <note>The hook travels at a speed of 4000/5000/6000.</note>
            <note>The affected enemy will be paused until the hook retracts.</note>
            <note>Colliding with a neutral creep will stop the hook for no effect.</note>
            <note>Clockwerk is silenced while travelling, so attempting to activate another ability mid-flight will not queue it for use when he arrives.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Clockwerk is a formidable ganker with nice farming capabilities who can be effective even with very few items in the early and mid game. This makes you comfortable at almost any lane; side lane, mid lane or solo lane are all viable options.</tips>
        <tips>Clockwerk has great synergy with high DPS nukers. Power Cogs can isolate a single enemy and set them up for AOE or single-target nukes.</tips>
        <tips>Clockwerk has two very powerful escape mechanisms in Power Cogs and Hookshot. Use them to enter fights or escape.</tips>
        <tips>Battery Assault works as a ministun, and is effective for interrupting channeled spells or teleports. This prevents heroes from casting spells with extended cast times.</tips>
        <tips>You can spam Rocket Flare to gain map control due to the vision it provides. Consider using it before the game starts to find out where enemy heroes are.</tips>
        <tips>You can utilize the global cast range of Rocket Flare to kill fleeing opponents.</tips>
        <tips>If a rocket flies over an empty neutral camp exactly during their respawn timer (every 1 minute), it will be counted as blocking (similar to ward blocking) and thus no neutrals will spawn there. However, this requires extremely precise timing, as the rocket needs to be 'physically' present there, not after it explodes.</tips>
        <tips>Clockwerk is a mortal threat to many heroes. However, his spells scale off late game. Be sure to have a strong ganking presence in the mid game to create space for your team.</tips>
        <tips>Necronomicon is also a good item to get on Clockwerk. The damage from the summoned units, mana burn, and the true sight all synergize well with Clockwerk's ability to trap enemies in his cogs.</tips>
        <tips>Force Staff is also a good choice to be able to quickly escape your own cogs, while leaving opponents trapped inside. This is especially useful against heroes that can rapidly deal melee damage (e.g. Slardar, Alchemist, Lifestealer,etc).</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Crystal Maiden</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <description>Rylai the Crystal Maiden is a ranged intelligence Hero used as a hard support and disabler. She is perhaps best known for her powerful global mana regeneration aura. This aura allows mana dependent allies to excel during the early to mid game and the laning phase, and allows her to constantly activate her own spells without needing to worry much about the mana costs. She also has a high amount of early game presence with just a few points in her Crystal Nova and Frostbite abilities. Crystal Nova is a powerful area-of-effect nuke that slows both attack and movement speeds of enemies within an area for several seconds, while Frostbite encases an enemy in a block of ice for several seconds, immobilizing it and doing moderate damage per second. Combining these two abilities together along with a laning partner's own spells often results in the quick death of an enemy hero. Although her strong early game presence is quickly lost due to her extreme frailty and poor mobility, she can still inflict a heavy amount of damage in teamfights later on if she is able to channel her deadly ultimate, Freezing Field. Her Arcane Aura, strong disabling and nuking prowess, relative ease of usage, and almost complete lack of item dependence makes her a reliable support caster that can be useful in any team.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.7"
            agilityBase="16"
            agilityGain="1.6"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="2.9"
            damageMinimum="35"
            damageMaximum="41"
            baseMoveSpeed="280"
            baseArmor="1.29" />
        <ability
            name="Crystal Nova"
            description="A burst of damaging frost slows enemy movement and attack rate in the targeted area."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="15"
            mana="100/120/140/160">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="700"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="400"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="3.5/4/4.5/5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100/150/200/250"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Movement Speed Slow"
                value="30%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Attack Speed Slow"
                value="20%"/>
            <altDescription description="The air temperature around Rylai drops rapidly, chilling all around her to the core." />
            <note>Provides vision within the area.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Frostbite"
            description="Encases an enemy unit in ice, prohibiting movement and attack, while dealing damage per second. Lasts 10 seconds on creeps level 6 or lower."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="10"
            mana="115/125/140/150">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="1.5/2/2.5/3"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Per Second"
                value="70"/>
            <altDescription description="Rylai channels winds from the Blueheart Glacier, imprisoning attackers in thick blocks of ice." />
            <note>True blink abilities cannot be used while under the effects of Frostbite.</note>
            <note>Frostbite does not prevent Phantom Strike, Duel, or Sun Ray's toggled movement. Only interrupts Icarus Dive if used during it, but does not prevent it from being used.</note>
            <note>Unique Attack Modifier abilities cannot be manually cast while Frostbite is active.</note>
            <note>Units that turn invisible while Frostbite is active are still revealed for Frostbite's duration.</note>
            <note>Lasts 10 seconds on all creeps of lvl 6 or less. This increases the overall damage to a total of 700.</note>
            <note>Damage is done at 0/1.0/2.0/3.0 seconds, dealing (at each skill level) 140/210/210/280 damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Arcane Aura"
            description="Gives additional mana regeneration to all friendly units on the map."
            ability="Aura"
            affects="Allies">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="Global"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Mana Regeneration"
                value="1/1.5/2/2.5"/>
            <altDescription description="Cold temperatures promote the essence of magic, causing Rylai's presence to allow spell usage in abundance." />
            <note>Stacks with the Aura given by Ring of Basilius.</note>
            <note>This bonus is doubled on Crystal Maiden.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Freezing Field"
            description="CHANNELED - Surrounds Crystal Maiden with random icy explosions that slow enemies and deal massive damage. Lasts 7 seconds."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            cooldown="150/120/90"
            mana="200/400/600">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="685"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Explosion Radius"
                value="230"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Slow"
                value="30% (50%*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="105/170/250 (170/250/310*)"/>
            <aghanims description="Increases damage and slow." />
            <altDescription description="Once the place of her exile, Icewrack has become an anchor for Rylai's frigid onslaught." />
            <note>Slow affects both movement and attack speed.</note>
            <note>The slow is applied on all enemies in the radius, even if they aren't hit by an explosion (lasts 1 second).</note>
            <note>Every 0.1 second an explosion occurs, for a total of 70 explosions.</note>
            <note>Theoretically if every explosion hit the same target it would do a total of 7350/11900/17500 (11900/17500/21700*) damage.</note>
            <note>If an enemy remained in the radius for the entire duration they would take an average of 828/1341/1972 (1341/1972/2446*) damage.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Crystal Nova is a large area of effect nuke that also slows your enemies. You can hit enemies from 1100 units away with it (700 casting range + 400 radius).</tips>
        <tips>Frostbite is a great disable which prevents the target from moving or attacking. It also interrupts channelling spells and teleports. Unfortunately, it does not prevent enemy heroes from casting spells (except Blink).</tips>
        <tips>Arcane Aura benefits the whole team greatly, especially one with a strong caster/ganker line-up.</tips>
        <tips>Generally, a couple points in Arcane Aura early is sufficient enough for the whole team. Adjust your skill build to the needs of your team.</tips>
        <tips>This bonus is doubled on Rylai herself, granting a whopping +5 bonus mana/s at max level.</tips>
        <tips>Freezing Field is an incredibly strong spell. However, it can be unpredictable and usually gets interrupted by your enemies very quickly. Freezing Field consumes a lot of mana, so use it sparingly.</tips>
        <tips>Many players choose not to skill Freezing Field until quite late in the game, as it is a situational spell that is most effective in large clashes; and its use consumes a huge amount of mana. However, its slow and gigantic (if unpredictable) damage can be very useful in early game, especially against enemies that lack the means to interrupt it. Let your decision be informed by enemy lineup as well as laning composition.</tips>
        <tips>Crystal Maiden can either babysit her team's carry on dual/triple lanes, or roam between the lanes to gank enemies.</tips>
        <tips>Always ward the woods. Wards should be bought over and over again to provide map control through the whole game.</tips>
        <tips>There is a temptation to use Crystal Nova to push lanes, but owing to its mana cost and long cooldown this isn't a good idea.</tips>
        <tips>If you have a few coins to spare - always buy items that boost your survivability, or get yourself an escape/positioning mechanism like Blink Dagger or Force Staff.</tips>
        <tips>Freezing Field must be used at the right time to avoid interruption and being focused. Generally speaking, in an encounter it is best used after the initial nuking phase; when the enemy's stuns are on cooldown (building a Black King Bar will provide immunity to stuns; but Crystal Maiden does not typically get much gold and this can be very difficult to build in a game where your team is not getting a lot of kills). If your team has an initiator with the capability to disable a group of enemies, such as Tidehunter or Enigma, Freezing Field should be used in synchronization with their mass disable. Using Freezing Field very often results in Rylai's death, and she rarely is able to channel it for its full duration, but if she can maintain it even for a few seconds it will be useful for her team.</tips>
        <tips>Although Freezing Field's damage can be upgraded with Aghanim's Scepter, to do so is to gild the lily; Freezing Field at level 3 is staggeringly powerful even without a scepter and it's wiser to build items that improve her chances of channeling it.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Dark Seer</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Ish'kafel the Dark Seer is a melee intelligence hero with versatile abilities that allow him to assist allies and greatly change the conditions of combat. His Vacuum in particular affects enemies in a large area and is a powerful crowd-control. It not only disorients and damages enemies, but also pushes them into a small area to follow up with area spells or to trigger other abilities, such as his Wall of Replica ultimate that turns the very power of enemies against them in the form of illusions that replicate their statistics. His other spells focus on buffing allies with speed, or in the case of his Ion Shell, granting an aura that radiates damage onto enemies who venture within it.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.3"
            agilityBase="12"
            agilityGain="1.2"
            intelligenceBase="29"
            intelligenceGain="2.7"
            damageMinimum="60"
            damageMaximum="66"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="5.71" />
        <ability
            name="Vacuum"
            description="Dark Seer creates a vacuum over the target area that sucks in enemy units, disrupting them and dealing damage."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="28"
            mana="100/130/160/190">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="250/350/450/550"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="40/80/120/160"/>
            <altDescription description="Ish'Kafel modifies the center of gravity to a place of his choosing." />
            <note>This ability interrupts channeling.</note>
            <note>Drags units over 0.3 seconds.</note>
            <note>Can drag units over cliffs.</note>
            <note>This ability destroys trees in a 275 radius.</note>
            <note>Doesn't work on invulnerable units.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Ion Shell"
            description="Surrounds the target unit with a bristling shield that damages enemy units in an area around it."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Units"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="9"
            mana="70/90/110/130">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="250"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="20"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Per Second"
                value="30/50/70/90"/>
            <altDescription description="The Dark Seer slices holes into the 'Land Behind the Wall,' causing prismatic energy to seep forth." />
            <note>Doesn't damage the target it is cast on.</note>
            <note>Damage is dealt in smaller amounts every 0.1 second.</note>
            <note>If cast on a unit that already has Ion Shell on it, the new Ion Shell will replace the old one.</note>
            <note>Can be cast on mechanical units.</note>
            <note>Total damage for each level is: 600/1000/1400/1800</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Surge"
            description="Charges a target friendly unit with power, giving it a brief burst of maximum movement speed."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Allied Units"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="12/11/10/9"
            mana="20/30/40/50">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="3/4.5/6/7.5"/>
            <altDescription description="Ish'Kafel once used his speed of mind to navigate the maze between the walls." />
            <note>Slowing effects from spells or items do not affect Surged units.</note>
            <note>Surged unit maintain maximum movement speed for the full duration, unless the Surge buff is removed (by Purge or other spells).</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Wall of Replica"
            description="Raises a wall of warping light that damages and creates replicas of any enemy hero who crosses it. Enemy replicas serve at the Dark Seer's will."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemy Heroes"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="1"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="100"
            mana="200/300/400">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500/900/1300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Wall Length"
                value="1000"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="15/30/45"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Illusion Damage Dealt"
                value="70%/80%/90% (100%/120%/140%*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Illusion Damage Recieved"
                value="300%"/>
            <blackKingBar description="The damage is blocked, illusion creation is not." />
            <aghanims description="Increases the damage dealt by illusions." />
            <altDescription description="The Dark Seer, while unable to return to his natural realm, can channel part of the prismatic wall with powerful strength of mind, sowing confusion amongst enemy ranks." />
            <note>Doesn't create illusions from other illusions.</note>
            <note>Everytime an enemy hero causes the wall to create an illusion, the wall deals 150 damage.</note>
            <note>Illusions are semi-transparent to enemy players.</note>
            <note>The wall is created perpendicular to the line between the Dark Seer and the target point.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>With a Stout Shield and healing items, Dark Seer can go to kill neutral creeps almost immediately.</tips>
        <tips>An advanced jungling tactic involves Smoke of Deceit. By combining it with Ion Shell, Dark Seer can jungle without taking any damage from creeps, as the only thing that removes the invisibility is proximity to an enemy hero or auto attacking a unit. In this way, Dark Seer can stack a single camp multiple times, cast Ion Shell on himself, pop Smoke, and stand at the camp until the creeps have been killed. Because of the steep cost of Smoke, it is advised that players do not use it without stacking camps first. As of the July 26th patch neutrals will now run away when attacked by an invisible enemy, players can still choose to use this method of jungling by chasing the creeps while invisible or casting on a weak neutral but the method will be far less efficient compared to before.</tips>
        <tips>If laning, be sure to harass enemies with Ion Shell by placing it on their melee creeps (for melee heroes) or ranged creeps (for ranged heroes). Additionally, placing Ion Shell on the second allied melee creep to arrive at the creep line is a good way to push the lane as well as create a moving damage-dealing creep that will chase enemy heroes.</tips>
        <tips>Be sure to take at least 1 early point of Surge, as it can help escaping ganks and chasing, as well as giving more mobility.</tips>
        <tips>When chasing, self-cast Ion Shell and run next to the enemy without attacking, using Surge if you need to catch up. Even better, use surge to body-block enemy heroes (that is, get in front of them to hinder their movement) and deliver auto-attacks without moving out of range of the Ion Shell.</tips>
        <tips>Wall of Replica is usually skilled after you've maxed both Ion Shell and Vacuum, as early game illusions don't deal much damage. Additionally, the relatively high mana cost at lower levels can be prohibitive, as you won't be left with much mana to cast other spells.</tips>
        <tips>AoE spells, especially those that require positioning, greatly benefit from Vacuum, as you can place all of them together to ensure a hit.</tips>
        <tips>Using Vacuum on enemy heroes to send them through your Wall of Replica will disallow foes from preventing illusions, as well as causing guaranteed damage from passing through the Wall.</tips>
        <tips>Due to Vacuum and Ion Shell's instant cast, your usefulness in large team fights permit Dark Seer to synergize extremely well with heroes such as Enigma and Jakiro. Make sure to cast these abilities with Black Hole and Ice Path/Macropyre/Liquid Fire to maximize AoE damage and maybe turn the tide in battle.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Dazzle</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Dazzle the Shadow Priest is a ranged intelligence Hero exhibiting abilities that bend the sustainability of both his allies and enemies, making him a viable support. While frail, he is capable of keeping his allies and himself from dying, causing his foes to waste time in a fruitless endeavor. Similarly to Slardar, Dazzle boasts abilities that deal physical damage instead of the usual magical. His first ability, Poison Touch, is a strong spammable disable, though mediocre in effects in the first levels. Out of all his abilities, Poison Touch is the only one that cannot pass through Magic immunity, but it will sustain itself when magic immunity is granted after the buff is placed. Shallow Grave is a solid survivability spell, allowing your allied targets to escape during serious encounters. Though it only prevents fatal damage, it cannot be purged, making it a full guarantee that Dazzle's target will survive for the duration. Shadow Wave is a chaining healing ability that dissipates the health gained to damage nearby enemies, having a potential of delivering a huge damage output when good positioning comes to play. His ultimate, Weave, is a large armor bending ability that not only increases his allies' armor, but also decreases his enemies'. With the fact that his abilities deal physical damage and that Dazzle himself has large attack damage, the chaotic combination with armor reduction really makes Dazzle a devastating Hero to go against.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.85"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="1.7"
            intelligenceBase="27"
            intelligenceGain="3.4"
            damageMinimum="41"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="2.0" />
        <ability
            name="Poison Touch"
            description="Casts a poisonous spell on an enemy unit, causing damage and slowness over time, and eventual paralysis. Poison Touch mini-stuns on impact. Slow increases per level."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="2"
            mantaStyle="0"
            cooldown="15/13/11/7"
            mana="100/115/130/145">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="500/900/1300"/>
            <altDescription description="One of the few Dezun rites used for offensive purposes, the paralytic enchantment often proves useful." />
            <note>Lvl 1: Slow target by 33% for 3 seconds.</note>
            <note>Lvl 2: Slow target by 33% for 2 seconds, then slow target by 66% for 1 second.</note>
            <note>Lvl 3: Slow target by 33% for 1 second, then slow target by 66% for 1 second, then slow target by 100% for 1 second.</note>
            <note>Lvl 4: Slow target by 33% for 1 second, then slow target by 66% for 1 second, then stun target for 1 second.</note>
            <note>The initial 0.01 second ministun will cancel channeling.</note>
            <note>The damage is not reduced by damage block abilities (such as Vanguard, Kraken Shell, etc.).</note>
            <note>After 3 seconds, damage occurs as 8 damage ticks over 7 seconds, dealing a total of 112/160/208/256 damage.</note>
            <note>Projectile is dodgeable.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Shallow Grave"
            description="An ally blessed with Shallow Grave, no matter how close to death, cannot die while under its protection."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Allies"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="60/45/30/15"
            mana="140/130/120/110">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="5"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="550/700/850/1000"/>
            <altDescription description="Only a seasoned acolyte of the Shadow can properly perform the rite of preventing death." />
            <note>HP cannot go below 1 while under the effects of Shallow Grave.</note>
            <note>Shallow Grave will not prevent Axe's Culling Blade ability from killing a hero.</note>
            <note>Does not prevent dying via Goblin Techies' Suicide Squad, Attack! or Bloodstone's Pocket Suicide.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Shadow Wave"
            description="Shadow Wave heals several allies, which in turn cause damage equal to their healing in a small area around them. Dazzle is always healed by Shadow Wave, and it does not count toward the number of targets."
            ability="Target Unit"
            affects="Allies"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="12/10/8/6"
            mana="80/90/100/110">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage Radius"
                value="185"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bounce Radius"
                value="475"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Number of Targets"
                value="3/4/5/6"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage/Heal"
                value="80/100/120/140*"/>
            <altDescription description="While it is a simplistic and routine rite among Shadow Priests, the Shadow Wave is also the most critical for success." />
            <note>Prioritizes allied heroes over creeps.</note>
            <note>If enemies are near multiple allied units affected by Shadow Wave, they can take multiple instances of damage.</note>
            <note>Can deal a maximum of 240/400/600/840 damage (Excludes Dazzle as a source of damage).</note>
            <note>(*) Heals allied units and damages enemies.</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Weave"
            description="Applies a buff that increases allied hero armor or decreases enemy hero armor in the target area over time."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Heroes"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="40"
            mana="100">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Range"
                value="2000"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="575 (775*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Armor Per Second"
                value="0.75/1/1.25 (1/1.25/1.5*)"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="24"/>
            <aghanims description="Increases radius and armor per second." />
            <altDescription description="His ethereal journey into the Nothl realm has allowed Dazzle to mend together the powers of light and dark, creating shifting waves of enchantments." />
            <note>Places a buff on units, so entering or leaving the area after the cast has no effect.</note>
            <note>Increases/Decreases armor by a maximum of 18/24/30/36*.</note>
            <note>Unobstructed sight (800 range day and night) is provided for 8 seconds.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Don't forget that Shadow Wave deals damage around your healed allies as well, roughly a Melee hero swing and a tiny bit more; a bit similar to Omniknight's Purification but with considerably less raw healing.</tips>
        <tips>Each level of upgrade for Shallow Grave makes it cost less mana; if you're having mana problems (and you likely will), consider upgrading it sooner rather than later.</tips>
        <tips>Your first skill can be any of the three depending on the situation; Poison Touch if you're hunting for first blood (with teammates, by yourself or with a single lane partner is probably not enough and can be risky in the event of a reversal), Shallow Grave if the enemy has not been spotted in their lanes and you suspect a possible gank incoming, and Shadow Wave if you're fighting an aggressive melee gank with an ally.</tips>
        <tips>Don't forget that the range of Shallow Grave increases with each level; it starts out less than your normal attack, but at level 4 goes to twice that length. You don't want to have an ally die just because you had to run in closer.</tips>
        <tips>Using Shallow Grave is the most important role Dazzle has, and one of the chief reasons why Dazzle is complicated; in using it you grant an ally or yourself five seconds where they cannot die. For newer players, it is often better to use it earlier than never; 2 seconds of life for an ally is better than none. More experienced players can gauge the situation of battles better, and can determine if burst damage has already been applied, amount and length of incoming stuns, and at whom they're directed, et cetera. In the early game laning phase, you can aggressively attempt a kill and then use Grave on yourself once you're near death; however, this can easily backfire due to burst damage and stun, preventing you from using the spell. In the mid game, your priority to grave are heroes with powerful abilities that haven't been used yet in an encounter, such as a Sand King Epicenter, a Tidehunter's Ravage, or an Enigma's Black Hole. Typically, the use of such ultimates would change the tide of battle in your favour, although this would only apply if those types of heroes are caught out of position, or are about to die before they can use it. Preventing a hard carry from dying and losing their gold is also important, but not if it means losing the teamfight and being able to push. In late game, keeping your hard carry alive becomes your top priority. There may be instances wherein you must choose between the life and death of allies, and it is very important to know who to prioritise (knowledge of priority will become second-nature with experience). For example, choosing between keeping Tidehunter alive after his Ravage has been used is a poor decision versus keeping your team's Lycan from dying, but if Tidehunter's death seems to be sure and Lycan's does not, you must make a decision very quickly. This is the difficulty of Dazzle.</tips>
        <tips>While Weave is a spell with a fairly simple effect it can massively increase both the deadliness and the durability of your team, especially if it is heavy in physical damage dealers who need to close with the enemy like Ursa and Sven.</tips>
        <tips>Learn to use Weave pre-emptively to maximise the armor buff/debuff for the team fight. In addition, it can be used to discourage your enemies from sieging a tower or attempting Roshan: as their armor deteriorates while they make an attempt, their chances of following up with a team fight in their favour becomes much lower.</tips>
        <tips>One of the main advantages of Shadow Wave is that, being a healing spell that can deal big damage in one time only if the situation is right (similarly to Earthshaker's Echo Slam), most enemies won't expect you to be a threat to them, and will chase you carelessly in a straight line. Decrease their armor with Weave or Medallion of Courage, then lead them into a wave of allied creeps. Once they're surrounded by the creeps, Shadow Wave them. Your attacker's diminished armor will not stop the raw physical damage. Then either slow him and chase after him, making sure your creeps stand around him for more Shadow Wave damage, or face him and Shallow Grave yourself if the enemy's damage output is too high for you to handle.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Death Prophet</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <description>Krobelus the Death Prophet is a ranged intelligence Hero who excels at pushing lanes. Like other casters, her abilities allow her to be less item dependent during the early game. As she learns Exorcism, Death Prophet can deal a huge amount of damage to towers and lone heroes alike, while healing at the end of the duration. Despite being a caster, Death Prophet has a relatively high Strength compared to other intelligence Heroes and she is mostly built as a tank. Her passive ability, Witchcraft, both grants her bonus movement speed and an increase her other abilities' effectiveness, making her a formidable ganker as well.</description>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="2.2"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.4"
            intelligenceBase="20"
            intelligenceGain="3.0"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="280"
            baseArmor="3.0" />
        <ability
            name="Crypt Swarm"
            description="Sends a swarm of winged beasts to savage enemy units in front of Death Prophet."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            damage="Magical"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            cooldown="8"
            mana="105/120/140/165">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Cast Range"
                value="600"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Damage"
                value="100/175/250/300"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="110 (Starting Radius) / 700 (Distance) / 300 (Final Radius)"/>
            <altDescription description="Krobelus' many trips to the grave gather a flock of the damned." />
            <note>Can hit units up to 1110 range away.</note>
            <note>Cooldown reduced by Witchcraft is: 7/6/5/4</note>
            <note>Mana Cost is reduce by max level Witchcraft to: 80/95/115/140</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Silence"
            description="Prevents enemy units in a target area from casting spells."
            ability="Target Point"
            affects="Enemies"
            blackKingBar="2"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="2"
            cooldown="15"
            mana="80">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Cast Range"
                value="900"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="425"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Duration"
                value="3/4/5/6"/>
            <altDescription description="Peering into the veil of her opponent's demise, Krobelus sees a silent future." />
            <note>Doesn't prevent usage of items.</note>
            <note>Cooldown is reduce with Witchcraft to: 14/13/12/11</note>
            <note>Mana Cost is reduce with Witchcraft to: 70/65/60/55</note>
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Witchcraft"
            description="Increases the potency of Death Prophet's spells, while providing a passive movement speed boost. Reduces mana costs and cooldowns of Crypt Swarm and Silence, and adds additional spirits to Exorcism."
            ability="Passive"
            affects="Self"
            mantaStyle="2">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Movement Speed"
                value="5%/10%/15%/20%"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Mana Cost Decrease on Crypt Swarm and Silence"
                value="10/15/20/25"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Cooldown Decrease on Crypt Swarm and Silence"
                value="1/2/3/4"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Bonus Exorcism Spirits"
                value="3/4/5/6"/>
            <mantaStyle description="Illusions get the bonus movement speed." />
            <altDescription description="With each death, Krobelus adds necromantic power to her repertoire." />
        </ability>
        <ability
            name="Exorcism"
            description="Unleashes evil spirits to drain the life of nearby enemy units and structures. At the end of the spell's duration, Death Prophet is healed in proportion to the damage dealt. Lasts 30 seconds."
            ability="No Target"
            affects="Enemy Units and Structures"
            damage="Physical"
            blackKingBar="0"
            linkensSphere="0"
            diffusalBlade="0"
            cooldown="115"
            mana="200/300/400">
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Radius"
                value="700"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Spirits"
                value="4/12/21"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Spirit Damage"
                value="53-58"/>
            <abilityAttributes
                name="Life Drain"
                value="25%"/>
            <altDescription description="Over time, the banshee remnants of her previous lives return to haunt the present." />
            <note>Radius specifies the area around Death Prophet where spirits will choose new targets.</note>
            <note>Spawns a maximum of 27 spirits.</note>
            <note>If a spirit gets 2000 range or more from Death Prophet, it will be destroyed.</note>
            <note>The spirits' damage is reduced by armor, but not by damage block (Stout Shield, etc.).</note>
            <note>The spirits will focus on the last hostile unit that was targeted.</note>
            <note>Healing will only occur after all spirits have returned to Death Prophet.</note>
            <note>Can damage siege creeps and structures.</note>
        </ability>
        <tips>Crypt Swarm is always maxed first, followed by Witchcraft; as Witchcraft greatly reduces the mana cost of Crypt Swarm as well as alleviating Krobelus' very low base movement speed. Maxing Witchcraft early also enhances Exorcism, which is a useful ability at all stages of the game.</tips>
        <tips>Always remember Exorcism's damage is physical, and as such Armor reduction increases its damage. Focusing on targets with low armour (Int and many Str heroes) will yield the best result of Exorcism. That said, its damage is a threat even to targets with very high armour.</tips>
        <tips>Put a single point in Silence early, as 3 seconds of silence is well worth the 80 mana it will cost you.</tips>
        <tips>In a large clash, Krobelus should be swooping around silencing and nuking enemy supports while eroding their health with Exorcism. Carries almost unfailingly have higher armor than supports, so her damage potential is highest when she focuses on the latter.</tips>
        <tips>Despite her abysmal base movement speed, with Witchcraft and Phase Boots Krobelus moves extremely fast and can often avoid damage simply by being faster than her aggressor. A Eul's Scepter of Divinity is also common pickup on her and will increase her movement speed to phenomenal levels. Krobelus tends to chase people around a lot with Exorcism, so high movement speed is a must and can also help the ghosts damage enemies around Krobelus while she is safe.</tips>
        <tips>Use Exorcism as early as is practically possible for clashes, as the sooner it is cast the sooner her spirits will return and heal her. Her spirits will easily harvest enough life to restore her HP entirely, and the conclusion of her ultimate can save Krobelus' life; as well as severely endanger the lives of her adversaries as she returns to battle with full health.</tips>
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Disruptor</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.4"
            intelligenceBase="22"
            intelligenceGain="2.5"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Doom</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="26"
            strengthGain="3.2"
            agilityBase="11"
            agilityGain="0.9"
            intelligenceBase="13"
            intelligenceGain="2.1"
            damageMinimum="53"
            damageMaximum="69"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="0.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Dragon Knight</name>
        <damageType>Melee/Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="2.8"
            agilityBase="19"
            agilityGain="2.2"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.7"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="52"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="3.71" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Drow Ranger</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="26"
            agilityGain="1.9"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.4"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="55"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="0.71" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Earthshaker</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.9"
            agilityBase="12"
            agilityGain="1.4"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="2.71" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Earth Spirit</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="21"
            strengthGain="2.9"
            agilityBase="17"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="2.4"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="3.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Elder Titan</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="24"
            strengthGain="2.3"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="23"
            intelligenceGain="1.6"
            damageMinimum="47"
            damageMaximum="57"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="3.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Ember Spirit</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="1.8"
            intelligenceBase="20"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="52"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Enchantress</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.0"
            agilityBase="19"
            agilityGain="1.8"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="2.8"
            damageMinimum="47"
            damageMaximum="57"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="0.71" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Enigma</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.1"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.0"
            intelligenceBase="20"
            intelligenceGain="3.4"
            damageMinimum="42"
            damageMaximum="48"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="4.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Faceless Void</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="1.6"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="2.65"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.5"
            damageMinimum="58"
            damageMaximum="64"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="4.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Gyrocopter</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="1.8"
            agilityBase="24"
            agilityGain="2.8"
            intelligenceBase="23"
            intelligenceGain="2.1"
            damageMinimum="41"
            damageMaximum="51"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="4.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Huskar</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="21"
            strengthGain="2.4"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.4"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.5"
            damageMinimum="42"
            damageMaximum="51"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Invoker</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
		<faction>Dire</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.7"
            agilityBase="20"
            agilityGain="1.9"
            intelligenceBase="22"
            intelligenceGain="2.5"
            damageMinimum="35"
            damageMaximum="41"
            baseMoveSpeed="280"
            baseArmor="1.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Io</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.6"
            intelligenceBase="23"
            intelligenceGain="1.7"
            damageMinimum="43"
            damageMaximum="52"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="0.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Jakiro</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="24"
            strengthGain="2.3"
            agilityBase="10"
            agilityGain="1.2"
            intelligenceBase="28"
            intelligenceGain="2.8"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="2.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Juggernaut</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="20"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="20"
            agilityGain="2.85"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="1.4"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="48"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="3.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Keeper of the Light</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="14"
            strengthGain="1.8"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.6"
            intelligenceBase="22"
            intelligenceGain="2.8"
            damageMinimum="40"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Kunkka</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="24"
            strengthGain="3.0"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.3"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.5"
            damageMinimum="50"
            damageMaximum="60"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="2.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Legion Commander</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="26"
            strengthGain="2.6"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="1.7"
            intelligenceBase="20"
            intelligenceGain="2.2"
            damageMinimum="57"
            damageMaximum="61"
            baseMoveSpeed="320"
            baseArmor="2.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Leshrac</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.6"
            agilityBase="23"
            agilityGain="1.7"
            intelligenceBase="26"
            intelligenceGain="3.0"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="49"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="3.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Lich</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="1.55"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="2.0"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="3.25"
            damageMinimum="42"
            damageMaximum="51"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Lifestealer</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="25"
            strengthGain="2.4"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="1.9"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.75"
            damageMinimum="57"
            damageMaximum="67"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="1.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Lina</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="1.5"
            agilityBase="16"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="27"
            intelligenceGain="3.2"
            damageMinimum="40"
            damageMaximum="58"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="1.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Lion</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.7"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="22"
            intelligenceGain="3.0"
            damageMinimum="42"
            damageMaximum="48"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Lone Druid</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.1"
            agilityBase="24"
            agilityGain="2.7"
            intelligenceBase="13"
            intelligenceGain="1.4"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="50"
            baseMoveSpeed="325"
            baseArmor="3.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Luna</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="15"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="2.8"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.85"
            damageMinimum="48"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="330"
            baseArmor="3.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Lycan</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.75"
            agilityBase="16"
            agilityGain="1.9"
            intelligenceBase="17"
            intelligenceGain="1.55"
            damageMinimum="58"
            damageMaximum="63"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="3.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Magnus</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="21"
            strengthGain="2.75"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="2.5"
            intelligenceBase="19"
            intelligenceGain="1.65"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="61"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="4.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Medusa</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
		<faction>Dire</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="14"
            strengthGain="1.65"
            agilityBase="20"
            agilityGain="2.5"
            intelligenceBase="19"
            intelligenceGain="1.85"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="50"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="1.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Meepo</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="1.6"
            agilityBase="23"
            agilityGain="1.9"
            intelligenceBase="20"
            intelligenceGain="1.6"
            damageMinimum="39"
            damageMaximum="45"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="4.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Mirana</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="1.85"
            agilityBase="20"
            agilityGain="2.75"
            intelligenceBase="17"
            intelligenceGain="1.65"
            damageMinimum="38"
            damageMaximum="49"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="1.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Morphling</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="24"
            agilityGain="3.0"
            intelligenceBase="17"
            intelligenceGain="1.5"
            damageMinimum="37"
            damageMaximum="46"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="1.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Naga Siren</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="21"
            strengthGain="2.3"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="2.75"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.95"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="46"
            baseMoveSpeed="320"
            baseArmor="6.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Nature's Prophet</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.8"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="1.9"
            intelligenceBase="21"
            intelligenceGain="2.9"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="3.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Necrophos</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.7"
            intelligenceBase="22"
            intelligenceGain="2.5"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="48"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="2.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Night Stalker</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.8"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="2.25"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.6"
            damageMinimum="57"
            damageMaximum="61"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="5.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Nyx Assassin</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="19"
            agilityGain="2.2"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="2.1"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="3.71" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Ogre Magi</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="3.2"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.55"
            intelligenceBase="17"
            intelligenceGain="2.4"
            damageMinimum="58"
            damageMaximum="64"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="6.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Omniknight</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="20"
            strengthGain="2.65"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.75"
            intelligenceBase="17"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="51"
            damageMaximum="61"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="4.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Outworld Devourer</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.85"
            agilityBase="24"
            agilityGain="2.0"
            intelligenceBase="26"
            intelligenceGain="3.3"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="61"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="5.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Phantom Assassin</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="20"
            strengthGain="1.85"
            agilityBase="23"
            agilityGain="3.15"
            intelligenceBase="13"
            intelligenceGain="1.0"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="48"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="4.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Phantom Lancer</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="2.7"
            agilityBase="23"
            agilityGain="4.2"
            intelligenceBase="21"
            intelligenceGain="2.0"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="67"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="3.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Phoenix</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.9"
            agilityBase="12"
            agilityGain="1.3"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="43"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="-0.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Puck</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="15"
            strengthGain="1.7"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="1.7"
            intelligenceBase="25"
            intelligenceGain="2.4"
            damageMinimum="47"
            damageMaximum="58"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="2.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Pudge</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
		<faction>Dire</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="25"
            strengthGain="3.2"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="1.5"
            damageMinimum="52"
            damageMaximum="58"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="1.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Pugna</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="1.2"
            agilityBase="16"
            agilityGain="1.0"
            intelligenceBase="26"
            intelligenceGain="4.0"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="320"
            baseArmor="1.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Queen of Pain</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.7"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="2.0"
            intelligenceBase="24"
            intelligenceGain="2.5"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="57"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="1.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Razor</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="21"
            strengthGain="1.7"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="2.0"
            intelligenceBase="19"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="47"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="2.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Riki</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="34"
            agilityGain="2.9"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="1.3"
            damageMinimum="48"
            damageMaximum="52"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="5.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Rubick</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.5"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="1.6"
            intelligenceBase="27"
            intelligenceGain="2.4"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="1.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Sand King</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="2.6"
            agilityBase="19"
            agilityGain="2.1"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="43"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="2.71" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Shadow Demon</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="2.2"
            intelligenceBase="23"
            intelligenceGain="2.7"
            damageMinimum="50"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="2.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Shadow Fiend</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="15"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="20"
            agilityGain="2.9"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="2.0"
            damageMinimum="35"
            damageMaximum="41"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="1.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Shadow Shaman</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.6"
            agilityBase="16"
            agilityGain="1.6"
            intelligenceBase="21"
            intelligenceGain="3.0"
            damageMinimum="47"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="1.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Silencer</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.2"
            agilityBase="16"
            agilityGain="2.1"
            intelligenceBase="27"
            intelligenceGain="2.5"
            damageMinimum="43"
            damageMaximum="57"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="1.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Skywrath Mage</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.5"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="0.8"
            intelligenceBase="27"
            intelligenceGain="3.6"
            damageMinimum="39"
            damageMaximum="49"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="0.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Slardar</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="21"
            strengthGain="2.8"
            agilityBase="17"
            agilityGain="2.4"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.5"
            damageMinimum="51"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="5.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Slark</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Escape</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="21"
            strengthGain="1.8"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.9"
            damageMinimum="54"
            damageMaximum="62"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="2.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Sniper</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.7"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="2.9"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="2.6"
            damageMinimum="36"
            damageMaximum="42"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="2.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Spectre</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="23"
            agilityGain="2.2"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.9"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="50"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="3.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Spirit Breaker</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="29"
            strengthGain="2.4"
            agilityBase="17"
            agilityGain="1.7"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="60"
            damageMaximum="70"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="5.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Storm Spirit</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="1.5"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="1.8"
            intelligenceBase="23"
            intelligenceGain="2.6"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="55"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="5.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Sven</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.7"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="2.0"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="1.3"
            damageMinimum="54"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="5.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Templar Assassin</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="2.1"
            agilityBase="23"
            agilityGain="2.7"
            intelligenceBase="20"
            intelligenceGain="2.0"
            damageMinimum="53"
            damageMaximum="59"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="4.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Terrorblade</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
		<faction>Dire</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="15"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="3.2"
            intelligenceBase="19"
            intelligenceGain="1.75"
            damageMinimum="48"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="315"
            baseArmor="7.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Tidehunter</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="3.0"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="1.5"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.7"
            damageMinimum="47"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="3.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Timbersaw</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.1"
            agilityBase="16"
            agilityGain="1.3"
            intelligenceBase="21"
            intelligenceGain="2.4"
            damageMinimum="48"
            damageMaximum="52"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="0.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Tinker</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.0"
            agilityBase="13"
            agilityGain="1.2"
            intelligenceBase="27"
            intelligenceGain="2.2"
            damageMinimum="49"
            damageMaximum="55"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="3.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Tiny</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="24"
            strengthGain="3.0"
            agilityBase="9"
            agilityGain="0.9"
            intelligenceBase="14"
            intelligenceGain="1.6"
            damageMinimum="61"
            damageMaximum="67"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="0.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Treant Protector</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="25"
            strengthGain="3.3"
            agilityBase="15"
            agilityGain="2.0"
            intelligenceBase="17"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="81"
            damageMaximum="89"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="1.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Troll Warlord</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="17"
            strengthGain="2.2"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="2.75"
            intelligenceBase="13"
            intelligenceGain="1.0"
            damageMinimum="38"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="2.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Tusk</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.3"
            agilityBase="23"
            agilityGain="2.1"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.7"
            damageMinimum="50"
            damageMaximum="54"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="3.29" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Undying</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.1"
            agilityBase="10"
            agilityGain="0.8"
            intelligenceBase="27"
            intelligenceGain="2.0"
            damageMinimum="57"
            damageMaximum="65"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="3.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Ursa</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Jungler</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="23"
            strengthGain="2.9"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="2.1"
            intelligenceBase="16"
            intelligenceGain="1.5"
            damageMinimum="45"
            damageMaximum="49"
            baseMoveSpeed="310"
            baseArmor="5.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Vengeful Spirit</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="2.6"
            agilityBase="27"
            agilityGain="2.8"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.75"
            damageMinimum="39"
            damageMaximum="53"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="3.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Venomancer</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Pusher</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="1.85"
            agilityBase="22"
            agilityGain="2.6"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.75"
            damageMinimum="41"
            damageMaximum="43"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="3.14" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Viper</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="20"
            strengthGain="1.9"
            agilityBase="21"
            agilityGain="2.5"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="46"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="2.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Visage</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.4"
            agilityBase="11"
            agilityGain="1.3"
            intelligenceBase="24"
            intelligenceGain="2.5"
            damageMinimum="48"
            damageMaximum="58"
            baseMoveSpeed="285"
            baseArmor="-0.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Warlock</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Initiator</role>
            <role>Lane Support</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="18"
            strengthGain="2.5"
            agilityBase="10"
            agilityGain="1.0"
            intelligenceBase="24"
            intelligenceGain="2.7"
            damageMinimum="46"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="2.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Weaver</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Agility</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="15"
            strengthGain="1.5"
            agilityBase="14"
            agilityGain="2.5"
            intelligenceBase="15"
            intelligenceGain="1.8"
            damageMinimum="50"
            damageMaximum="60"
            baseMoveSpeed="290"
            baseArmor="1.0" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Windranger</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Escape</role>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="15"
            strengthGain="2.5"
            agilityBase="17"
            agilityGain="1.4"
            intelligenceBase="22"
            intelligenceGain="2.6"
            damageMinimum="44"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="1.43" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Witch Doctor</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="16"
            strengthGain="1.8"
            agilityBase="13"
            agilityGain="1.4"
            intelligenceBase="24"
            intelligenceGain="2.9"
            damageMinimum="51"
            damageMaximum="61"
            baseMoveSpeed="305"
            baseArmor="0.86" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Wraith King</name>
        <damageType>Melee</damageType>
        <attribute>Strength</attribute>
        <faction>Dire</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Carry</role>
            <role>Disabler</role>
            <role>Durable</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="22"
            strengthGain="2.9"
            agilityBase="18"
            agilityGain="1.7"
            intelligenceBase="18"
            intelligenceGain="1.6"
            damageMinimum="54"
            damageMaximum="56"
            baseMoveSpeed="300"
            baseArmor="3.57" />
    </hero>
    <hero>
        <name>Zeus</name>
        <damageType>Ranged</damageType>
        <attribute>Intelligence</attribute>
        <faction>Radiant</faction>
        <roles>
            <role>Nuker</role>
            <role>Support</role>
        </roles>
        <attributes
            strengthBase="19"
            strengthGain="2.3"
            agilityBase="11"
            agilityGain="1.2"
            intelligenceBase="20"
            intelligenceGain="2.7"
            damageMinimum="41"
            damageMaximum="49"
            baseMoveSpeed="295"
            baseArmor="1.57" />
    </hero>
</heroes>